[
  {
    "id": 1632583832411,
    "question": "Trapezius upperNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Trapezius upperNerve: **Spinal accessory**Roots: **C3, C4::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632584659631,
    "question": "Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: [...]Root: [...]",
    "answer": "Rhomboid Major and minor Nerve: **Dorsal scapular**Root: **C5::1** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632585459577,
    "question": "Serratus anteriorNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Serratus anteriorNerve: **Long thoracic**Roots: **C5, C6, C7::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632585980961,
    "question": "Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: [...] Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Pectoralis major and minor Nerve: **Lateral pectoral; Medial pectoral::2** Roots: **C5, C6, C7, C8, T1::**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632586355131,
    "question": "Latissimus dorsiNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Latissimus dorsiNerve: **Thoracodorsal**Roots: **C6, C7, C8::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632602639458,
    "question": "Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minorNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Supra-spinatus & infra-spinatus & teres minorNerve: **Suprascapular, Suprascapular, Axillary::3**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632603210049,
    "question": "Deltoid Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Deltoid Nerve: **Axillary**Roots: **C5, C6::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632603825345,
    "question": "Biceps & BrachialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Biceps & BrachialisNerve: **Musculocutaneous. \"70% have dual radial n. (brachialis)\"**Roots: **C5, C6::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632604220448,
    "question": "BrachioradialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "BrachioradialisNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C5, C6::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632604586453,
    "question": "Extensor carpi radialisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Extensor carpi radialisNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C6, C7::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632604987361,
    "question": "TricepsNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "TricepsNerve: **Radial**Roots: **C6, C7, C8::3** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632605382915,
    "question": "Pronator teresNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Pronator teresNerve: **Median**Roots: **C6, C7::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632605712159,
    "question": "Flexor carpi radialisNerve: [...]Nerve Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Flexor carpi radialisNerve: **Median**Nerve Roots: **C6, C7::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632606650556,
    "question": "Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Extensor digitorum longus / Indicis / digit minimi Nerve: **Radial (Posterior interosseous branch)**Roots: **C7, C8::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632607927259,
    "question": "Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve:Digits 2 & 3 [...] Digits 4 & 5 [...] Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Flexor digitorum profundus Nerve:Digits 2 & 3 **Ant. interosseous branch of median** Digits 4 & 5 **Ulnar** Roots: **C7, C8, T1::3** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632608454705,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Flexor digitorum superficialis**Nerve: **Median**Roots: **C7, C8, T1::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632609063882,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Flexor pollicis longus**Nerve: **Ant. interosseous of median nerve.**Roots: **C8, T1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632609333324,
    "question": "Abductor pollicis brevisNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Abductor pollicis brevisNerve: **Median nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632609678977,
    "question": "Opponens pollicis Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Opponens pollicis Nerve: **Median nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632609993443,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Adductor pollicis**Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632610198911,
    "question": "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**First dorsal & abd dig minimi, dorsal interosseus** Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632668240414,
    "question": "Subscapularis nerve: [...]roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Subscapularis nerve: **Upper and lower subscapular nerves::2**roots: **C5, C6::2**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632668793027,
    "question": "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Flexor Carpi Ulnaris** Nerve: **Ulnar nerve**Roots: **C8, T1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1632669279060,
    "question": "[...] nerve: [...] roots: [...] \"no major\"",
    "answer": "**Extensor Pollicis Longus and Brevis** nerve: **Posterior interosseous branch of the radial nerve** roots: **C7, C8::2** \"no major\"",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634494760413,
    "question": "IliacusNerve: [...]Roots: [...] no majorpsoasNerve: [...]Roots: [...] no major",
    "answer": "IliacusNerve: **Femoral**Roots: **L2, L3** no majorpsoasNerve: **lumbar spinal nerves**Roots: ** L1, L2 and L3** no major (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634495044155,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Gluteus medius/min & tensor fascia::3**Nerve: **Superior gluteal**Roots: **L4, L5, S1::3** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634495281811,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Gluteus maximus**Nerve: **Inferior gluteal**Roots: **L5, S1, S2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634495520352,
    "question": "QuadricepsNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "QuadricepsNerve: **Femoral**Roots: **L2, L3, L4::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634495698652,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Tibialis anterior::m.**Nerve: **Deep peroneal**Roots: **L4, L5::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634495916107,
    "question": "Extensor hallucis longusNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Extensor hallucis longusNerve: **Deep peroneal**Roots: **L5, S1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634496143730,
    "question": "Flexor hallucis longusNerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Flexor hallucis longusNerve: **Tibial**Roots: **L5, S1, S2::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634496357419,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Tibialis posterior**Nerve: **Tibial**Roots: **L5, S1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634496519285,
    "question": "[...]Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "**Peroneus longus & brevis::2**Nerve: **Superficial peroneal**Roots: **L5, S1::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634496682784,
    "question": "Gastrocnemius & soleus: Nerve: [...]Roots: [...]",
    "answer": "Gastrocnemius & soleus: Nerve: **Tibial**Roots: **S1, S2::2** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634497130711,
    "question": "[...] Nerve: [...]Roots: [...] no major",
    "answer": "**Adductor Magnus, Longus, Brevis::1 of 3** Nerve: **Obturator nerve**Roots: **L2, L3, L4::3** no major",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634497501648,
    "question": "Biceps Femoris (long & Short, Semimembranosus, and Semitendinosus) Nerve: [...] Roots: [...] no major",
    "answer": "Biceps Femoris (long & Short, Semimembranosus, and Semitendinosus) Nerve: **sciatic nerve Tibial division & common peroneal division (to short head of biceps femoris)::2 + caveat** Roots: **L5, S1, S2::3** no major",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634824812838,
    "question": "[...] is an injury to sheath of the nerve (but the axon remains intact.)translates to slower signal conduction (onset/peak latency +/- duration) along the axon.",
    "answer": "**demyelination** is an injury to sheath of the nerve (but the axon remains intact.)translates to slower signal conduction (onset/peak latency +/- duration) along the axon.",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634825217345,
    "question": "Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons)is known as [...] It can present as a [...] drop in [...] with stim. [...]",
    "answer": "Failure of an AP to propagate past an area of demyelination (along healthy axons)is known as **conduction block.** It can present as a **>20% - >50%::%range2#'s** drop in **CMAP amplitude** with stim. **across the area of injury or L/R comparison::location 2**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634825966117,
    "question": "demyelination affects the speed of signal conduction along a nervethus NCS's (CMAP and SNAP) parameters effected include:[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "demyelination affects the speed of signal conduction along a nervethus NCS's (CMAP and SNAP) parameters effected include:**o/p latency****CV****duration (temporal dispersion)**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634826379576,
    "question": "[...] injuries affect the amplitude on nerve conduction waveform",
    "answer": "**Axonal** injuries affect the amplitude on nerve conduction waveform",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634826588748,
    "question": "[...]: A nerve injury that begins in a “dying back” fashion and affects the nerve distally and ascends proximally[...]: A nerve injury that degenerates distally. The nerve segment proximal to the injury site is essentially intact",
    "answer": "**Axonal Degeneration**: A nerve injury that begins in a “dying back” fashion and affects the nerve distally and ascends proximally**Wallerian Degeneration**: A nerve injury that degenerates distally. The nerve segment proximal to the injury site is essentially intact",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634827686906,
    "question": "[...] is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unitresults in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury):[...] [...] [...]",
    "answer": "**Collateral sprouting** is repair in which a neurite sends off axons of an intact motor unit and innervates muscle fibers of an injured motor unitresults in MUAP changes (evidnece of chronic injury):**polyphasic waveforms** **increased duration** **increased amplitude**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634827804416,
    "question": "[...] is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original pathIt will travel approximately [...]/d or [...]mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact.",
    "answer": "**Axonal regrowth** is a process of repair in which the nerve regrows down its original pathIt will travel approximately **1 mm**/d or **1 in./**mo if the supporting connective tissue remains intact.",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634844708560,
    "question": "Sunderland ClassificationTYPE 1[...]TYPE 2[...]TYPE 3Type 2 + [...] injuryTYPE 4Type 3 + [...] injuryTYPE 5Type 4 + [...]",
    "answer": "Sunderland ClassificationTYPE 1**Conduction block (neuropraxia)::2**TYPE 2**Axonal injury (axonotmesis)::2**TYPE 3Type 2 + **Endoneurium** injuryTYPE 4Type 3 + **Perineurium** injuryTYPE 5Type 4 + **Epineurium injury (neurotmesis)::2**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634845635485,
    "question": "[...] is A theoretical local block that occurs when reversing the stimulator’s cathode and anode. This hyperpolarizes the nerve, thus inhibiting the production of an action potential",
    "answer": "**Anodal Block** is A theoretical local block that occurs when reversing the stimulator’s cathode and anode. This hyperpolarizes the nerve, thus inhibiting the production of an action potential",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634846151435,
    "question": "[...] stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS)stimulus intensity set too [...] - [...]- Amplitudes [...]stimulus intensity set too [...] - falsely [...] - falsely [...]",
    "answer": "**Supramaximal stimulus** stim. intensity 20% above the max stimulus to generate an AP (typically used for NCS)stimulus intensity set too **high** - **Altered waveforms (spreads through tissues beyond surface electrodes)**- Amplitudes **remain unchanged**stimulus intensity set too **low** - falsely **lower amplitude** - falsely **prolonged latency**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634846534576,
    "question": "process of averaging improves the [...] by a factor that is the square root of the number of averages performed.",
    "answer": "process of averaging improves the **Signal to Noise Ratio (S:N)** by a factor that is the square root of the number of averages performed.",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634846665871,
    "question": "Stimulus ArtifactThis is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized byAppropriate: [...] placement[...]",
    "answer": "Stimulus ArtifactThis is a defect seen at the time the stimulus is applied to the skin and represents current spread to the electrode. It can be minimized byAppropriate: **ground and stimulator (anode and cathode)::equipment factor 2** placement**Cleansing the skin from dirt, perspiration, and lotions::pt factor**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634855351602,
    "question": "A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing [...] and the vertical axis representing [...] or gaineach cube is a [...]",
    "answer": "A grid is projected on the screen with the horizontal axis representing **sweep speed (msec)::name, unit** and the vertical axis representing **sensitivity (mV)::name, unit** or gaineach cube is a **division**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634857611089,
    "question": "[...] is the time required for an electrical stimulus to initiate an evoked potential (fastest axon)[...] is the time for the majority of the axons",
    "answer": "**Onset/distal latency (CMAP)** is the time required for an electrical stimulus to initiate an evoked potential (fastest axon)**Peak latency (SNAP)** is the time for the majority of the axons",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634857821391,
    "question": "[...] is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the [...]Normal values are generally >[...] m/sec in the upper limbs and >[...] m/sec in the lower limbs",
    "answer": "**conduction velocity** is the speed an impulse travels along a nerve primarily dependent on the integrity of the **myelin**Normal values are generally >**50** m/sec in the upper limbs and >**40** m/sec in the lower limbs",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634858756029,
    "question": "EMG/NCS Conduction VelocityCV for a newborn is 50% that of an adult. At 1 year, it is 80% that of an adult. It is equal to an adult by [...] yearsAfter the [...] decade, the CV decreases [...] m/sec per decade",
    "answer": "EMG/NCS Conduction VelocityCV for a newborn is 50% that of an adult. At 1 year, it is 80% that of an adult. It is equal to an adult by **3–5::#~#** yearsAfter the **5th** decade, the CV decreases **1–2::range** m/sec per decade",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634859337870,
    "question": "[...] reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibersCMAP (or SNAP) [...] reductions are due to injury to [...]",
    "answer": "**Amplitude** reflects the number of activated muscle fibers or sensory nerve fibersCMAP (or SNAP) **amplitude::same** reductions are due to injury to **axons**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634859587160,
    "question": "[...] is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing.it is a measure of [...] of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing",
    "answer": "**duration::NCS parameter** is measured from the initial deflection from baseline to the first baseline crossing.it is a measure of **synchrony** of the sensory nerve fibers and individual muscle fibers firing",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634860078926,
    "question": "[...] reflects the range of conduction velocities of the fastest and slowest nerve fibers.",
    "answer": "**Temporal dispersion** reflects the range of conduction velocities of the fastest and slowest nerve fibers.",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1634899647729,
    "question": "[...] = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring oneswhen comparing a [...] stimulation, a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.)amplitude drop of [...] is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAPamplitude drop of [...] is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP",
    "answer": "**Phase Cancellation** = when stimulated, the APs of one axon may be out of sync with neighboring oneswhen comparing a **proximal to distal** stimulation, a drop in amplitude and increase in duration occurs (nl.)amplitude drop of **50%::%** is considered normal when recording a proximal SNAPamplitude drop of **15%::%** is considered normal when recording a proximal CMAP",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635019472566,
    "question": "SNAPs are normal in [...] injury",
    "answer": "SNAPs are normal in **Pre-ganglionic::pre/post** injury",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635019716271,
    "question": "active and reference pickup should be [...] cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by [...] them allSave for [...] which will still be normal",
    "answer": "active and reference pickup should be **> 4:: >/</#** cm apart. Less than this distance will alter the waveform parameters by **decreasing::inceasing/decreasing** them allSave for **onset latency** which will still be normal",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635020127681,
    "question": "CMAP potential should be [...] with an initial [...] deflection",
    "answer": "CMAP potential should be **biphasic::morphology** with an initial **negative (upward)** deflection",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635020914592,
    "question": "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to...1.) [...]2.) [...]3.) [...]",
    "answer": "CMAP: if an initial positive deflection exists, it may be due to...1.) **Inappropriate placement of active electrode (from MP)**2.) **conduction from other muscles (stim^)**3.) **Anomalous innervations (M. gruber)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635021140498,
    "question": "Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to...[...][...] [...]",
    "answer": "Recording electrode falsely decreased amplitude can be due to...**active and reference electrodes too close together****position off from motor point** **submaximal stimulation**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635041533555,
    "question": "[...] is an NCS analogue to a monosynaptic reflex",
    "answer": "**H-reflex** is an NCS analogue to a monosynaptic reflex",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635041785457,
    "question": "H-reflex is initiated with a [...] at a [...] duration (1.0 msec).causing an [...] [...] response to the spinal cord, and then an [...] [...] response back to the electrode",
    "answer": "H-reflex is initiated with a **submaximal stimulus** at a **long** duration (1.0 msec).causing an **orthodromic::ortho/anti** **sensory::motor/sensory** response to the spinal cord, and then an **orthodromic::ortho/anti** **motor::motor/sensory** response back to the electrode",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635042321707,
    "question": "H-reflex limitations1) [...] 2) [...]3) [...]",
    "answer": "H-reflex limitations1) **can not localize lesion** 2) **cannot distinguish between acute and chronic**3) **NOT a specific finding to S1 radiculopathy**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635042859845,
    "question": "[...] is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP. It is produced using a [...] duration, [...] stimulation",
    "answer": "**F-wave** is a small late motor response occurring after the CMAP. It is produced using a **short** duration, **supramaximal** stimulation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635043035494,
    "question": "F-wave May be helpful in polyneuropathies and [...] but not overly useful in radiculopathies",
    "answer": "F-wave May be helpful in polyneuropathies and **plexopathies** but not overly useful in radiculopathies",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635043806903,
    "question": "In [...] morphology and latency remain constant with each stimulation at the appropriate intensity",
    "answer": "In **H-reflex::F/H** morphology and latency remain constant with each stimulation at the appropriate intensity",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635280551223,
    "question": "EMG increased insertional activity may be seen in both [...] and [...] conditions",
    "answer": "EMG increased insertional activity may be seen in both **neuropathic** and **myopathic** conditions",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635280677487,
    "question": "EMG rare conditions, where [...] has occurred, insertional activity may be decreased",
    "answer": "EMG rare conditions, where **muscle atrophy** has occurred, insertional activity may be decreased",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635343921792,
    "question": "a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur:1.) [...] which sound like a [...] 2.) [...] which sound like a [...]",
    "answer": "a needle inserted into muscle should be silent at rest if placed near the NMJ (motor endplate), two waveforms can occur:1.) **MEPPs (EP noise)** which sound like a **sea-shell murmur** 2.) **EPPs (EP spikes)** which sound like a **sputtering fat**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635344950262,
    "question": "EMG: spontaneous activity at rest (not NMJ) in general represents [...] of muscle",
    "answer": "EMG: spontaneous activity at rest (not NMJ) in general represents **denervation** of muscle",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635345446958,
    "question": "Both fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves are usually seen together in [...] muscle EMG, hallmarks are sounding like (Fib): [...] and (Psw): [...] and their [...] of firing",
    "answer": "Both fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves are usually seen together in **denervated** muscle EMG, hallmarks are sounding like (Fib): **\"rain on a tin roof”** and (Psw): **\"dull thuds\"** and their **regularity::timing** of firing",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635345626379,
    "question": "a numeric grading scale to quantify fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves on a scale from _ to _ [...]",
    "answer": "a numeric grading scale to quantify fibrillation potentials and positive sharp waves on a scale from _ to _ **+1 to +4**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635348955146,
    "question": "[...]",
    "answer": "**Fibrillation potentials::wave form**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635348979166,
    "question": "[...]",
    "answer": "**Complex repetitive discharges::wave form**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635349652423,
    "question": "[...] sound like a [...] spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by [...] 2/2 [...]",
    "answer": "**complex repetetive discharges** sound like a **motor boat** spontaneous, polyphasic APs originating from a group muscle fibers fire in near synchrony by **ephaptic transmission** 2/2 **collateral sprouting**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635349679112,
    "question": "[...]",
    "answer": "**Myotonic discharges**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635349963884,
    "question": "[...] are classicly associated w/ [...] [...] single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a [...] sound",
    "answer": "**myotonic discharges** are classicly associated w/ **myopathies::disease category** **biphasic::waveform** single muscle fiber AP's arise after mechanical irritation hallmark sign: smooth change in rate and amplitude with a **“dive bomber”** sound",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635350242203,
    "question": "[...] has the appearance of a MUAP with an [...] firing patternIts hallmark sign is a much [...] frequency with a [...] sound",
    "answer": "**fasciculation** has the appearance of a MUAP with an **irregular** firing patternIts hallmark sign is a much **slower** frequency with a **“corn popping”** sound",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635354513231,
    "question": "[...]: rhythmic groups of MUAPs firing repetitivelyclinicaly present as slow continuous [...] sounds like [...] hallmark sign is the [...] within and between each discharge",
    "answer": "**Myokymic discharges**: rhythmic groups of MUAPs firing repetitivelyclinicaly present as slow continuous **“worm-like” quivering** sounds like **“marching soldiers.”** hallmark sign is the **semi-regularity** within and between each discharge",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635354589536,
    "question": "Myokymic discharges are most commonly seen in [...]",
    "answer": "Myokymic discharges are most commonly seen in **radiated-induced neuropathy**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635355111069,
    "question": "[...]: high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic [...] sound and [...] appearance",
    "answer": "**Neuromyotonic discharges**: high-frequency, repetitive discharges with progressively decremental amplitudes Hallmark signs on EMG include characteristic **“pinging”** sound and **Tornado-like** appearance",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635355218931,
    "question": "Neuromyotonic discharges classically seen in [...].",
    "answer": "Neuromyotonic discharges classically seen in **neuromyotonia (Isaac’s syndrome)::eponym**.",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635356223797,
    "question": "exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a [...]unlike CMAP initial deflection is [...]. can consist of up to [...] phases",
    "answer": "exertinal muscle fiber activity can be electrically recorded and summated as a **MUAP**unlike CMAP initial deflection is **- or +**. can consist of up to **4** phases",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635356761982,
    "question": "MUAP amplitude: represents the muscle fiber density, measured from the most positive to the most negative peakIt can be increased from [...], A sign that inury is becoming [...]",
    "answer": "MUAP amplitude: represents the muscle fiber density, measured from the most positive to the most negative peakIt can be increased from **reinnervation**, A sign that inury is becoming **chronic::timing**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635356972387,
    "question": "MUAP Rise Time: represents the time it takes the MUAP to go from trough to the peak of the negative wave. It represents [...] to the motor unit.",
    "answer": "MUAP Rise Time: represents the time it takes the MUAP to go from trough to the peak of the negative wave. It represents **needle position** to the motor unit.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635357066029,
    "question": "MUAP Duration increases (>15 msec) as the motor unit territory increases 2/2 [...]",
    "answer": "MUAP Duration increases (>15 msec) as the motor unit territory increases 2/2 **collateral sprouting/reinervation::pathology**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635357257414,
    "question": "polyphasicity (5 phases) results from [...] and is [...] in timing however, this can occur normally 15% [...] or 30% [...] or in the elderly",
    "answer": "polyphasicity (5 phases) results from **reinnervation/collateral sprouting::patho-phys** and is **chronic** in timing however, this can occur normally 15% **(concentric needle)** or 30% **(monopolar needle)** or in the elderly",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635441527779,
    "question": "[...]: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP. 2/2 early [...] → very slowly conducting",
    "answer": "**satellite potentitals**: time-locked potentials that trail the MUAP. 2/2 early **re-inervation** → very slowly conducting",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635441729623,
    "question": "[...] spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ [...] (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise",
    "answer": "**cramp discharge** spontaneous repetitive firing of MUAPs assoc w/ **metabolic disturbances** (broad dz category) and pregnancy / strenuous exercise",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635442490969,
    "question": "[...] refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween [...] and [...] diseases",
    "answer": "**Recruitment** refers to addition successive MU's to increase force of contraction. can help decide bewtween **neruopathic** and **myopathic** diseases",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635442589329,
    "question": "EMG MUAP recruitment pattern follows: \"The rule of [...]\"",
    "answer": "EMG MUAP recruitment pattern follows: \"The rule of **5's**\"",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635442835550,
    "question": "[...] most commonly seen in myopathic conditions that result in a loss of muscle fibers.",
    "answer": "**Early recruitment::recruitment pattern** most commonly seen in myopathic conditions that result in a loss of muscle fibers.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635442892105,
    "question": "[...] most commonly seen in neuropathic conditions",
    "answer": "**Reduced recruitment::recruitment pattern** most commonly seen in neuropathic conditions",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1635442996549,
    "question": "Motor unit recruitment. (A) Normal. (B) [...] (C) [...]",
    "answer": "Motor unit recruitment. (A) Normal. (B) **Early (myopathic)** (C) **Decreased (neuropathic)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1642360144912,
    "question": "this is a [...] needle electrode",
    "answer": "this is a **Monopolar** needle electrode",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1642360215210,
    "question": "this is a [...] needle electrode",
    "answer": "this is a **Concentric** needle electrode",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1642360548139,
    "question": "Monopolar needle advantages (PM&R)Records more [...] and larger [...]",
    "answer": "Monopolar needle advantages (PM&R)Records more **positive sharp waves (more abnormal activity in general)** and larger **MUAP's**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1642360628814,
    "question": "Concentric needle advantagesless [...]",
    "answer": "Concentric needle advantagesless **interference**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1644938245116,
    "question": "[...]: results from [...] muscle fibersthat are [...] by [...]",
    "answer": "**complex repetetive discharge::EMG wave form**: results from **denervated** muscle fibersthat are **reinnervated** by **collateral sprouting**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1644938661000,
    "question": "[...]: spontaneous discharges originating from the [...] or its [...] prior to its terminal branchesresults in [...] muscle fiber contractionIf associated with [...], they are considered pathological",
    "answer": "**fasciculation**: spontaneous discharges originating from the **motor neuron** or its **axon** prior to its terminal branchesresults in **intermittent::timing** muscle fiber contractionIf associated with **FIBs or PSWs**, they are considered pathological",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1644938837151,
    "question": "[...] EMG finding are associated with [...] diseases (broad category)",
    "answer": "**fasciculations** EMG finding are associated with **Anterior horn cell** diseases (broad category)",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456299854,
    "question": "Radiculopathy (sensory vs motor)most commonly presents as: [...] complaints, [...] complaints, or [...] complaints\"in descending order\"",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy (sensory vs motor)most commonly presents as: **pure sensory** complaints, **sensori-motor** complaints, or **pure motor** complaints\"in descending order\"",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456352724,
    "question": "RadiculopathyNCSs are typically [...]",
    "answer": "RadiculopathyNCSs are typically **normal**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456399829,
    "question": "RadiculopathyA pure sensory injury would demonstrate a [...] EMG.",
    "answer": "RadiculopathyA pure sensory injury would demonstrate a **negative** EMG.",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456482021,
    "question": "Radiculopathy[...] occur without structural abnormalities on MRI or EMG",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy**can::can / cannot** occur without structural abnormalities on MRI or EMG",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456691843,
    "question": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causesH—[...]I—[...]M—[...]A—[...]D—[...]A—[...]M—[...]",
    "answer": "Unncommon Radiculopathy causesH—**Herpes zoster**I—**Inflammatory::whole category**M—**Metastasis**A—**Arachnoiditis**D—**Diabetes mellitus**A—**Abscess**M—**Mass**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456744529,
    "question": "Radiculopathy common cuases include [...] and [...]",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy common cuases include **herniated disc** and **spinal stenosis**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645456959463,
    "question": "role of NCS in Radiculopathy is to evaluate [...] to explain the patient’s symptoms",
    "answer": "role of NCS in Radiculopathy is to evaluate **superimposed pathology** to explain the patient’s symptoms",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645457114777,
    "question": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located [...] to the DRGCMAP: Normal or reduced amplitudeCMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is...purely [...][...] or[...] has already occurred(not snesory)",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located **proximal** to the DRGCMAP: Normal or reduced amplitudeCMAP Amp: can be normal if the injury is...purely **demyelinating****incomplete** or**reinnervation** has already occurred(not snesory)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645457156251,
    "question": "H-reflex: Possibly abnormal in an [...] radiculopathy but not pathognomonic",
    "answer": "H-reflex: Possibly abnormal in an **S1** radiculopathy but not pathognomonic",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645457219206,
    "question": "F-waves: [...] sensitive / specific for a radiculopathy.",
    "answer": "F-waves: **Not::are / are not** sensitive / specific for a radiculopathy.",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645458276223,
    "question": "EMG for Dx radiculopathyabnormal findings in [...] muscles innervated by the same [...] but different [...]",
    "answer": "EMG for Dx radiculopathyabnormal findings in **two or more::#** muscles innervated by the same **spinal nerve root** but different **peripheral nerves**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645458442560,
    "question": "EMG for Dx radiculopathyIdeally, [...] muscles ([...] peripheral muscles + [...]) should be evaluated",
    "answer": "EMG for Dx radiculopathyIdeally, **6** muscles (**5** peripheral muscles + **paraspinals**) should be evaluated",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645458674630,
    "question": "EMG Radiculopathy DxClassically, [...] found in [...] different muscles innervated by different peripheral nerves but same spinal root.",
    "answer": "EMG Radiculopathy DxClassically, **FIBs or PSWs::2** found in **2::#** different muscles innervated by different peripheral nerves but same spinal root.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645458765425,
    "question": "EMG Radiculopathy DxFibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: [...][...][...]incomplete or missed by random sampling",
    "answer": "EMG Radiculopathy DxFibs and Sharps may NOT be found if: the lesion is: **demyelinating****pure sensory****chronic**incomplete or missed by random sampling",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645460781827,
    "question": "Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates [...] responses of the nervous system to an [...]. SSEP's represent the function of the [...] pathway using afferent potentials",
    "answer": "Somatosensory Evoked Potential study evaluates **time-locked** responses of the nervous system to an **external stimulus**. SSEP's represent the function of the **DCML** pathway using afferent potentials",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645460999266,
    "question": "SSEP's initiated by a repetitive [...] stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the [...] or [...]",
    "answer": "SSEP's initiated by a repetitive **submaximal::intensity** stimulation of a sensory nerve, mixed nerve, or dermatome, and is recorded from the **spine** or **scalp**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645461081074,
    "question": "Somatosensory evoked potential (SSEP) monitors for problems such as (a) [...], (b) [...], or (c) [...]",
    "answer": "Somatosensory evoked potential (SSEP) monitors for problems such as (a) **peripheral nerve injuries**, (b) **CNS lesions (eg. MS)**, or (c) **intraoperative monitoring (eg. spinal surgery)**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645461182084,
    "question": "MS SSEP's are seen 90% of the time, with the lower limb more likely to be abnormal than the upper limb. most common abnormality is the prolonged [...]. Amplitude reduction or absence can also be seen",
    "answer": "MS SSEP's are seen 90% of the time, with the lower limb more likely to be abnormal than the upper limb. most common abnormality is the prolonged **interpeak latencies**. Amplitude reduction or absence can also be seen",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645461247846,
    "question": "SSEP nerves most commonly used for testing are the [...] for the upper limb and the [...] nerve for the lower limb",
    "answer": "SSEP nerves most commonly used for testing are the **median** for the upper limb and the **tibial** nerve for the lower limb",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645461606685,
    "question": "SSEP's[...] considered useful for radiculopathies",
    "answer": "SSEP's**are not::are / are not** considered useful for radiculopathies",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645479841403,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: Decreased [...]Decreased [...]Prolonged [...]Abnormal [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **0** daysAbnormality: Decreased **recruitment**Decreased **recruitment interval**Prolonged **F-wave**Abnormal **H-reflex**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645479959457,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: Decreased [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **4** daysAbnormality: Decreased **CMAP amplitude**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645501859049,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **7** daysAbnormality: **Abnormal spontaneous activity in the paraspinals::EMG finding and location**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645501994296,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] daysAbnormality: [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **14** daysAbnormality: **Abnormal spontaneous activity in the limbs::EMG finding and location**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645502140506,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] days Abnormality: [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **21** days Abnormality: **Abnormal activity present in both the paraspinals and limbs::EMG finding and llocation**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645502246398,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] Abnormality: [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **5–6 weeks::2 #'s** Abnormality: **Reinnervation begins / polyphasic::EMG finding**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645502319352,
    "question": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: [...] Abnormality: [...]",
    "answer": "Chronology of Electrodiagnostic FindingsTime: **6 months to 1 year::2 #'s** Abnormality: **Increased amplitude from reinnervated motor unit**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645548616098,
    "question": "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury[...] causing a transient ischemia or edema with [...] Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to [...]",
    "answer": "Etiologies Demeylinating Injury**Focal compression** causing a transient ischemia or edema with **paranodal intussusceptions** Chronic diseases causing degradation of myelin leading to **peripheral neuropathies**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645549591433,
    "question": "NCS of demeylinating injuries Latency is typicaly [...] and Amplitude is typically [...]",
    "answer": "NCS of demeylinating injuries Latency is typicaly **prolonged** and Amplitude is typically **normal**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645549933849,
    "question": "CMAP with low amplitude can be 2/2... 1.) temporal dispersion or 2.) decreased # of axons [...] of the AP is prolonged in temporal dispersioncausing, [...] to remain the same",
    "answer": "CMAP with low amplitude can be 2/2... 1.) temporal dispersion or 2.) decreased # of axons **duration** of the AP is prolonged in temporal dispersioncausing, **area under the curve** to remain the same",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645551959707,
    "question": "supramaximal stimulation is achieved by [...] until the [...] of the waveform is no longer increasing",
    "answer": "supramaximal stimulation is achieved by **increasing stimulation** until the **amplitude** of the waveform is no longer increasing",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645552005946,
    "question": "Ulnar nerve studies measurement is a common source of errorit is best to keep the elbow [...] and in the [...] for the entire study",
    "answer": "Ulnar nerve studies measurement is a common source of errorit is best to keep the elbow **flexed 90o** and in the **same position** for the entire study",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645552722252,
    "question": "Active electrode: The active electrode, also referred to as E1 or G1 should be placed over the...[...] during motor studies. directly over the [...] during sensory studies.",
    "answer": "Active electrode: The active electrode, also referred to as E1 or G1 should be placed over the...**muscle belly** during motor studies. directly over the **nerve** during sensory studies.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645552788686,
    "question": "The reference electrode (sometimes called the E2 or G2) should be placed.. on a nearby [...]",
    "answer": "The reference electrode (sometimes called the E2 or G2) should be placed.. on a nearby **tendon or bone::2**",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645552978621,
    "question": "When stimulating proximal and distal sites, the waveforms should be [...] in morphology and duration",
    "answer": "When stimulating proximal and distal sites, the waveforms should be **similar** in morphology and duration",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645553014774,
    "question": "If you are not sure which nerve is being stimulated NCS, check for [...]",
    "answer": "If you are not sure which nerve is being stimulated NCS, check for **physiological response**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645553174804,
    "question": "You can estimate the amount of axonal loss in an acute peripheral nerve lesionif you compare the amplitude of the CMAP to the [...]",
    "answer": "You can estimate the amount of axonal loss in an acute peripheral nerve lesionif you compare the amplitude of the CMAP to the **unaffected side**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645553800315,
    "question": "[...] are muscle fiber AP's recorded from a injured muscle or muscle with impaired innervation",
    "answer": "**Positive sharp waves (PSWs)** are muscle fiber AP's recorded from a injured muscle or muscle with impaired innervation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645553944511,
    "question": "[...] are spontaneous AP's of single muscle fibers firing autonomously. This can occur in the presence of impaired innervation",
    "answer": "**Fibrillation potentials (fibs)** are spontaneous AP's of single muscle fibers firing autonomously. This can occur in the presence of impaired innervation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645554388519,
    "question": "‘denervation potentials’ is a misnomer for [...]. (ex fibs, PSW, CRD's, cramps, mokymic, and fascic)Irritation can be cuased by [...] and [...] muscle disease, and local muscle [...].",
    "answer": "‘denervation potentials’ is a misnomer for **spontaneous activity**. (ex fibs, PSW, CRD's, cramps, mokymic, and fascic)Irritation can be cuased by **metabolic** and **inflammatory** muscle disease, and local muscle **trauma**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645555815392,
    "question": "analyzing motor unit morphologycan be made more accurate by freezing the screen or by using a [...]",
    "answer": "analyzing motor unit morphologycan be made more accurate by freezing the screen or by using a **trigger and delay line**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645556029913,
    "question": "EMG MUAP Decreased amplitude may be seen in [...]",
    "answer": "EMG MUAP Decreased amplitude may be seen in **myopathies::dz category**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645557256185,
    "question": "Motor unit [...] is a better measure of pathology than polyphasicity it will be [...] in neuropathic processesand [...] in myopathic disorders",
    "answer": "Motor unit **duration** is a better measure of pathology than polyphasicity it will be **increased** in neuropathic processesand **decreased** in myopathic disorders",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645558118535,
    "question": "EMG no abnormal spontaneous activity should be noted in any of the [...] lesions unless there is conduction block, in which case you would find [...]",
    "answer": "EMG no abnormal spontaneous activity should be noted in any of the **demyelinating** lesions unless there is conduction block, in which case you would find **decreased recruitment**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645558248386,
    "question": "(SNAPs) and (CMAPs) amplitudes begin to decrease within [...] after nerve injury.",
    "answer": "(SNAPs) and (CMAPs) amplitudes begin to decrease within **several days** after nerve injury.",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645559375259,
    "question": "Radiculopathysensory NCS are always [...] unless there is [...]",
    "answer": "Radiculopathysensory NCS are always **normal** unless there is **coexisting pathology e.g., carpal tunnel syndrome**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645559407196,
    "question": "Radiculopathy if SNAP abnormalities are found, it is important to [...]",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy if SNAP abnormalities are found, it is important to **rule out other lesions**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645559679922,
    "question": "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be [...]",
    "answer": "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be **normal**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645559756513,
    "question": "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be normal*However, in a [...] lesion it may be affected",
    "answer": "RadiculopathyIn general, CMAP in NCS will be normal*However, in a **severe radicular** lesion it may be affected",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645559874992,
    "question": "Radiculopathyeven if a lesion causes axonal damage, the CMAP amplitude could still be normal*because muscles have [...].",
    "answer": "Radiculopathyeven if a lesion causes axonal damage, the CMAP amplitude could still be normal*because muscles have **input from multiple nerve roots**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645560209990,
    "question": "Radiculopathy In reinnervation with sprouting of collateral axons, MUAP abnormalities such as [...] and [...] motor units may be present",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy In reinnervation with sprouting of collateral axons, MUAP abnormalities such as **long duration** and **polyphasic** motor units may be present",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645560312184,
    "question": "Radiculopathy Recruitment abnormalities, if seen... would be typical of a [...] recruitment patternincluding: [...] motor units firing at a [...] rate",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy Recruitment abnormalities, if seen... would be typical of a **neuropathic** recruitment patternincluding: **few** motor units firing at a **high** rate",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645560521274,
    "question": "RadiculopathyEMG in general will be able to assess only [...] injury to motor fibers",
    "answer": "RadiculopathyEMG in general will be able to assess only **axonal** injury to motor fibers",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645560988200,
    "question": "[...] are classified as affecting primarily [...], or both. and by part of the nerve predominantly affected – [...], or both",
    "answer": "**Peripheral neuropathies** are classified as affecting primarily **motor or sensory fibers**, or both. and by part of the nerve predominantly affected – **axon or myelin**, or both",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645561053241,
    "question": "Most peripheral neuropathies affect the [...] segment of the nerve",
    "answer": "Most peripheral neuropathies affect the **distal** segment of the nerve",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645561288328,
    "question": "EMG findings are usually [...] in peripheral neuropathy",
    "answer": "EMG findings are usually **negative** in peripheral neuropathy",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645561337699,
    "question": "EMG findings are usually negative in peripheral neuropathy, unless there is an [...]",
    "answer": "EMG findings are usually negative in peripheral neuropathy, unless there is an **axonal motor neuropathy**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645561900391,
    "question": "[...] – the entire length of the nerve displays a slower conduction velocity. This is typically seen in dz's such as [...] and [...]",
    "answer": "**Uniform demyelination** – the entire length of the nerve displays a slower conduction velocity. This is typically seen in dz's such as **Charcot–Marie–Tooth** and **leukodystrophy**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562119245,
    "question": "[...] – uneven degree of demyelination of different nerve fibers throughout the course of the nerve which presents as [...] Dz example:[...][...][...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "**Segmental demyelination** – uneven degree of demyelination of different nerve fibers throughout the course of the nerve which presents as **temporal dispersion** Dz example:**AIDP / CIDP****Arsenic****MM****AIDS****LYME****Leprosy**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562369751,
    "question": "[...] – localized area of demyelinationwhich presents as a decrease in conduction velocity [...] the lesion ex. [...] usually evident if there is a more than [...] m/s drop",
    "answer": "**Focal nerve slowing** – localized area of demyelinationwhich presents as a decrease in conduction velocity **across** the lesion ex. **cubital tunnel or entrapment neuropathy** usually evident if there is a more than **10** m/s drop",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562554470,
    "question": "[...] – an area of severe focal demyelination where AP cannot propagate. [...] amplitude with [...] stimulation",
    "answer": "**Conduction block** – an area of severe focal demyelination where AP cannot propagate. **decreased::nl or dec** amplitude with **proximal::proximal/distal** stimulation",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562691517,
    "question": "CMAP amplitude distal to a conduction block will be [...]",
    "answer": "CMAP amplitude distal to a conduction block will be **unaffected::affected / unaffected**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562944991,
    "question": "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [...] to the lesion latencies/CV will be [...][...] EMG findings",
    "answer": "In axonal injury you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation **both Distal & Proximal::distal or proximal** to the lesion latencies/CV will be **normal*::abnormal/normal****+::+/-** EMG findings",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645562991097,
    "question": "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation [...] to the lesion drop in amp [...]%",
    "answer": "In conduction block you will see a decrease in CMAP amplitude with stimulation **proximal::distal or proximal** to the lesion drop in amp **20-50::2 # range**%",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645563422086,
    "question": "Pure axonal injuryEtiology: (a) focal crush(b) [...](c) [...](d) [...]NCS latency and CV will be [...] EMG activity will be [...]",
    "answer": "Pure axonal injuryEtiology: (a) focal crush(b) **stretch (traction)**(c) **transection**(d) **peripheral neuropathies**NCS latency and CV will be **normal::abdnormal/normal** EMG activity will be **abdnormal::abdnormal/normal**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645563805690,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes:[...][...][...] [...]",
    "answer": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from muscle fibers includes:**FIBs****PSWs****Complex repetitive discharges** **Myotonic discharges**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645563879198,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes:[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Abnormal spontaneous activity from a motor neuron/axon includes:**Fasciculation potentials*****Myokymic discharges****Neuromyotonic discharges****Cramp discharge**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645564091618,
    "question": "[...] EMG activity",
    "answer": "**cramp discharges** EMG activity",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645638675207,
    "question": "AIN branches from the median nerve innervate (3 P's):[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "AIN branches from the median nerve innervate (3 P's):**Flexor digitorum profundus (FDP 1 and 2)****Flexor pollicis longus (FPL)****Pronator quadratus (PQ)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645639168857,
    "question": "through the carpal tunnel, the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous [...][...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "through the carpal tunnel, the median n. innervates 4 muscles, +1 cutaneous **Lumbricals (1, 2)****Opponens pollicis****Abductor pollicis brevis****Flexor pollicis brevis (superficial)****Digital cutaneous branches** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645639731345,
    "question": "Median n. Course:runs medial to the [...] in the distal upper armcontinues down the humerus and runs under the [...] at the medial epicondyle the [...] overlies the nerve in the proximal forearmnerve then passes between the [...] muscle and continues down under the [...]",
    "answer": "Median n. Course:runs medial to the **brachial a.** in the distal upper armcontinues down the humerus and runs under the **ligament of Struthers** at the medial epicondyle the **antebrachial fascia** overlies the nerve in the proximal forearmnerve then passes between the **two heads of the PT** muscle and continues down under the **FDS muscle**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645639951551,
    "question": "[...]: 2 cm bone spur 3 to 6 cm proximal to the medial epicondyle. It is connected to the epicondyle by a ligament in 1% of the population",
    "answer": "**LIGAMENT OF STRUTHER**: 2 cm bone spur 3 to 6 cm proximal to the medial epicondyle. It is connected to the epicondyle by a ligament in 1% of the population",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645640132038,
    "question": "Ligament of Struthers EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal median [...] [...] at [...] siteEMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: [...]",
    "answer": "Ligament of Struthers EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal median **SNAP and CMAP::2 NCS tests** **conduction velocity (onset) / or conduction block (amp)::2 NCS paramaters** at **above elbow** siteEMG: Abnormal in which median nerve-innervated muscles: **All (including the PT)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645640298859,
    "question": "bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an [...]EDX pres: similar to the [...]",
    "answer": "bicipital aponeurosis median n. can be injured by entrapment or hematoma compression resulting from an **ABG / venipuncture::2**EDX pres: similar to the **LOS**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645640526148,
    "question": "General Rule of ThumbAn entrapment mononeuropathy: is commonly named for the muscle compressing the nerve. That muscle is usually [...]",
    "answer": "General Rule of ThumbAn entrapment mononeuropathy: is commonly named for the muscle compressing the nerve. That muscle is usually **unaffected::affected or unaffected**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645640628809,
    "question": "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal [...] SNAPsAbnormal CMAPs at [...] EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: [...]",
    "answer": "Pronator Teres Syndrome EDX findings:NCS: Abnormal **median nerve*** SNAPsAbnormal CMAPs at **above elbow site::in conduction block** EMG: Abnormal activity in which median n. muscles: **All EXCEPT the PT*** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645641052132,
    "question": "Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex findingpt may demonstrate a positive [...] signor Inability to [...] Sensation is [...]",
    "answer": "Anterior interosseous syndrome Phys-Ex findingpt may demonstrate a positive **“OK”** signor Inability to **make a fist** Sensation is **spared**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645642342009,
    "question": "[...]% of people with clinical carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) can have a normal EDX study",
    "answer": "**10**% of people with clinical carpal tunnel syndrome (CTS) can have a normal EDX study",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645642749114,
    "question": "[...] from concomitant DMT2 or cervical radiculopathy increases the risk of CTS",
    "answer": "**Double crush syndrome** from concomitant DMT2 or cervical radiculopathy increases the risk of CTS",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645643462420,
    "question": "CTS clinical presSensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the [...]. Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: [...]",
    "answer": "CTS clinical presSensation is abnormal to the lateral 3–1/2 fingers of the hand except at the **base of the thumb**. Muscle weakness can be noted which muscles: **“LOAF”**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645643662574,
    "question": "CTS EDX findings [...] studies are more sensitive because larger fibers are more affected than the slightly smaller fibers",
    "answer": "CTS EDX findings **Sensory::Motor/Sensory** studies are more sensitive because larger fibers are more affected than the slightly smaller fibers",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645643994061,
    "question": "median NCSsdemyelinating lesion at the carpal tunnel results in [...] of both motor and sensory if demyelination caused conduction block or axonal loss, the distal CMAP and SNAP [...] will be decreased",
    "answer": "median NCSsdemyelinating lesion at the carpal tunnel results in **prolonged distal latencies** of both motor and sensory if demyelination caused conduction block or axonal loss, the distal CMAP and SNAP **amplitudes** will be decreased",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644051626,
    "question": "CTS EDX studyThe study of [...] of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from [...]",
    "answer": "CTS EDX studyThe study of **distal segments** of the median nerve is helpful in distinguishing CTS from **peripheral neuropathy**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644316751,
    "question": "If CTS patient has normal \"routine\" median nerve conduction studies (NCS); further testing is performed using more sensitive NCSs known as [...]",
    "answer": "If CTS patient has normal \"routine\" median nerve conduction studies (NCS); further testing is performed using more sensitive NCSs known as **comparison studies (ie. median to ulnar)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644384075,
    "question": "median-versus-ulnar comparison tests a difference of > [...] msec is considered abnormal",
    "answer": "median-versus-ulnar comparison tests a difference of > **0.5** msec is considered abnormal",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644509642,
    "question": "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: Prolonged latency plus decreased amplitudeCMAP: Prolonged latency",
    "answer": "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Moderate**SNAP: Prolonged latency plus decreased amplitudeCMAP: Prolonged latency",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644558959,
    "question": "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: Prolonged latency CMAP: Normal",
    "answer": "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Mild**SNAP: Prolonged latency CMAP: Normal",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645644599262,
    "question": "CTS SEVERITYNCS[...]SNAP: AbsentCMAP: Prolonged latency and decr. Amplitude",
    "answer": "CTS SEVERITYNCS**Severe**SNAP: AbsentCMAP: Prolonged latency and decr. Amplitude",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710207455,
    "question": "[...]: numbness or dysesthesias in 1st - 4th digits. sx exacerbated during sleep (most common sx) and relieved with wrist shaking",
    "answer": "**Mild CTS::CTS severity**: numbness or dysesthesias in 1st - 4th digits. sx exacerbated during sleep (most common sx) and relieved with wrist shaking",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710297488,
    "question": "[...]: continuous sensory deficits in the median nerve distribution, involving the entire palm and radiating proximally. ability to handle fine objects is impaired",
    "answer": "**Moderate CTS::CTS severity**: continuous sensory deficits in the median nerve distribution, involving the entire palm and radiating proximally. ability to handle fine objects is impaired",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710333408,
    "question": "[...]: sensory loss and thenar muscular atrophy",
    "answer": "**Severe CTS::CTS severity**: sensory loss and thenar muscular atrophy",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710466838,
    "question": "CTS etiologyobesitydiabetes[...][...][...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "CTS etiologyobesitydiabetes**thyroid disease****RA tenosynovitis****CHF****renal failure****mass (tumor, hematoma)****pregnancy**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710635957,
    "question": "CTS treatments (conserative)[...][...] [...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "CTS treatments (conserative)**Ergonomic modification****hand splint** **NSAIDs****steroid injection****diuretics****vitamin B6**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645710741702,
    "question": "CTS treatmentOrthotics: Hand splint neutral to [...]-degree extension",
    "answer": "CTS treatmentOrthotics: Hand splint neutral to **30**-degree extension",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645711632016,
    "question": "CTS surgical indicationsx's of numbness/paresthesias, severe pain despite [...]",
    "answer": "CTS surgical indicationsx's of numbness/paresthesias, severe pain despite **a trial of conservative treatment::modifier**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645711830241,
    "question": "CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with...Symptoms >[...] months in durationPositive Phalen’s test in <[...] secondsany [...]any [...]",
    "answer": "CTS Poor outcome with conservative management may occur with...Symptoms >**10 ** months in durationPositive Phalen’s test in <**10** secondsany **mod-severe clinical sx's**any **mod-severe EDX findings**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645714383502,
    "question": "[...] aka [...] or [...] may exclusively affect the [...]",
    "answer": "**Neuralgic amyotrophy** aka **Parsonage-Turner Syndrome** or **idiopathic brachial plexopathy** may exclusively affect the **anterior interosseous nerve (AIN)::nerve**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1645714594415,
    "question": "Clinically, (sx's) Sensory deficits in the [...] can help to differentiate a proximal median neuropathy from CTS",
    "answer": "Clinically, (sx's) Sensory deficits in the **palm / thenar eminence** can help to differentiate a proximal median neuropathy from CTS",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646357253567,
    "question": "NCS of demeylinating injuries Amplitude typically normal: but may be decreased due to... [...] and [...] or [...]",
    "answer": "NCS of demeylinating injuries Amplitude typically normal: but may be decreased due to... **temporal dispersion** and **phase-cancellation** or **conduction block**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646436858242,
    "question": "[...]: median to ulnar nerve “crossover” in the mid-forearm that involves [...] fibers most common, occurring in about [...] of median nerves",
    "answer": "**Martin-Gruber anastomosis**: median to ulnar nerve “crossover” in the mid-forearm that involves **motor** fibers most common, occurring in about **1/3** of median nerves",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646437038540,
    "question": "Martin-Gruber anastamosis, Median n. now innervates...[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Martin-Gruber anastamosis, Median n. now innervates...**adductor pollicis (ADP)****abductor digiti minimi (ADM)****first dorsal interossei (FDI)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646437145133,
    "question": "When present, the MGA can lead to unusual sparing of muscles after severe proximal [...] nerve injury or [...] distally",
    "answer": "When present, the MGA can lead to unusual sparing of muscles after severe proximal **ulnar** nerve injury or **CTS::diagnosis** distally",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646437197923,
    "question": "a proximal [...] nerve injury can lead to unexpectedly widespread denervation in the presence of the MGA",
    "answer": "a proximal **median** nerve injury can lead to unexpectedly widespread denervation in the presence of the MGA",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646437507271,
    "question": "MGA can be recognized by a Median n. CMAP that is larger w/ stim. at the [...] than at the [...] In such cases, obtain the [...] CMAP from the [...]...this will be smaller with stimulation at the [...] compared with the [...]",
    "answer": "MGA can be recognized by a Median n. CMAP that is larger w/ stim. at the **elbow** than at the **wrist** In such cases, obtain the **Ulnar n.** CMAP from the **APB**...this will be smaller with stimulation at the **elbow** compared with the **wrist**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646437688988,
    "question": "in MGA An initial [...] deflection of the median nerve CMAP at [...] is seen,which is not seen at the [...]. Only seen with concomitant [...]",
    "answer": "in MGA An initial **positive** deflection of the median nerve CMAP at **elbow** is seen,which is not seen at the **wrist**. Only seen with concomitant **CTS**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646438490416,
    "question": "In MGA one can see an artificially [...] this is 2/2 an unreasonably small [...]",
    "answer": "In MGA one can see an artificially **fast CV::increased/decreased, parameter** this is 2/2 an unreasonably small **latency difference**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646438561156,
    "question": "[...]connection of the [...] median nerve to the [...] ulnar nerve",
    "answer": "**RICHE-CANNIEU ANASTOMOSIS**connection of the **recurrent branch of the::specific part** median nerve to the **deep motor branch of the::specific part** ulnar nerve",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646438605744,
    "question": "Riche-cannieuWhile recording over the APB muscle, CMAP is absent with [...] nerve stimulation but present with stimulation of the [...] nerve",
    "answer": "Riche-cannieuWhile recording over the APB muscle, CMAP is absent with **median** nerve stimulation but present with stimulation of the **ulnar** nerve",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1646683692695,
    "question": "EMG phases equal the [...]Normally, motor unit potentials have [...] or fewer phases",
    "answer": "EMG phases equal the **# of BL crossings +1**Normally, motor unit potentials have **4** or fewer phases",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647103466552,
    "question": "Ulnar N. Course descends along the medial surface of the [...]. It runs within fascia known as the [...]. between the medial epicondyle and olecranon called the [...] enters the forearm through an aponeuroosis aka the [...] joining the two heads of the [...] At the wrist, beween the [...] called Guyon’s canal",
    "answer": "Ulnar N. Course descends along the medial surface of the **medial head triceps**. It runs within fascia known as the **arcade of Struthers (AOS)**. between the medial epicondyle and olecranon called the **retrocondylar groove** enters the forearm through an aponeuroosis aka the **cubital tunnel** joining the two heads of the **flexor carpi ulnaris** At the wrist, beween the **pisiform and hamate::2** called Guyon’s canal (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647103617784,
    "question": "through Guyon’s canal, Ulnar n. splits into 3 branches1. [...]2. [...]3. [...]",
    "answer": "through Guyon’s canal, Ulnar n. splits into 3 branches1. **Superficial sensory branch**2. **Hypothenar branch**3. **Deep motor branch**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647103877894,
    "question": "Ulnar N Hypothenar branch innervated 3 muscles[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Ulnar N Hypothenar branch innervated 3 muscles**Opponens digiti quinti****Abductor digiti quinti****Flexor digiti quinti**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647104276650,
    "question": "Ulnar N. Deep motor branch innervates m.:[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Ulnar N. Deep motor branch innervates m.:**Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)****Adductor pollicis****Interossei (Palmar and Dorsal)****Lumbricals (4th & 5th)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647104569842,
    "question": "The Ulnar n. aka \"1-1/2\" Nerve1-1/2 muscle of the forearm[...][...]1-1/2 muscles of the thumb[...][...]1-1/2 muscle class of the palm*[...][...]",
    "answer": "The Ulnar n. aka \"1-1/2\" Nerve1-1/2 muscle of the forearm**1 Flexor carpi ulnaris****1/2 Flexor digitorum profundus (3, 4)**1-1/2 muscles of the thumb**1 Adductor pollicis****1/2 Flexor pollicis brevis (deep head)**1-1/2 muscle class of the palm***1 Interosse (all)****1/2 lumbricals (3, 4)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647104786183,
    "question": "About the middle of the forearm, the Ulnar n. gives rise to the [...] branch,provides sensory innervation to the [...].",
    "answer": "About the middle of the forearm, the Ulnar n. gives rise to the **ulnar palmar cutaneous** branch,provides sensory innervation to the **proximal hypothenar (medial palm) area**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647104944884,
    "question": "[...] nerve: arising 8 cm proximal to [...]",
    "answer": "**Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC)** nerve: arising 8 cm proximal to **Guyon’s canal**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647105191122,
    "question": "Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC) nerve: normal or abnormalNCS are [...] in a handle-bar neuropathy at the wrist but [...] in more proximal compressions ie. CUTS",
    "answer": "Dorsal ulnar cutaneous (DUC) nerve: normal or abnormalNCS are **normal** in a handle-bar neuropathy at the wrist but **abnormal** in more proximal compressions ie. CUTS",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647110795565,
    "question": "[...]: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the [...] to the [...]pt demonstrates involvement of [...]Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in [...]",
    "answer": "**ARCADE OF STRUTHERS**: fascial band in the medial arm that connects the **brachialis** to the **triceps brachii-medial**pt demonstrates involvement of **all ulnar nerve innervated muscles and sensory**Phys-ex: Wrist flexion may result in **radial deviation** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647111040570,
    "question": "Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... [...]: unopposed [...] causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the [...] joints",
    "answer": "Arcade of Struthers Syndrome may cause... **Ulnar claw hand**: unopposed **extensor digitorum communis (EDC)** causes partial finger flexion of the 4th and 5th PIP and DIP due to extension of the **MCP** joints",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647111366937,
    "question": "[...] sign: inability to hold a paper by pure thumb [...] weakness). pt substitutes [...] muscle, causing flexion of the DlP joint",
    "answer": "**Froment’s** sign: inability to hold a paper by pure thumb **adduction (adductor pollicis::action/muscle** weakness). pt substitutes **FPL** muscle, causing flexion of the DlP joint",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647111553994,
    "question": "[...] sign: Inability to adduct the [...] weakness)",
    "answer": "**Wartenberg’s** sign: Inability to adduct the **5th digit (palmar interossei::body part/muscle** weakness)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647112052561,
    "question": "[...] a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracturepresents same as [...] syndrome",
    "answer": "**TARDY ULNAR NERVE PALSY** a ulnar neuropathy that can occur years after a distal humeral fracturepresents same as **arcade of struthers** syndrome",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647112847952,
    "question": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings..SNAP: Abnormal [...] findings (if severe)CMAP: abnormal [...] (in conduction block)CMAP: normal [...] (in conduction block)Approximately [...] msec decrease in [...] or a [...] drop in amplitude",
    "answer": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDx findings..SNAP: Abnormal **sup. sensory (5th digit) & DUC** findings (if severe)CMAP: abnormal **above elbow::site** (in conduction block)CMAP: normal **wrist and B. elbow sites::site** (in conduction block)Approximately **10 - 15::2# range** msec decrease in **CV** or a **20%** drop in amplitude",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647113097463,
    "question": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar GrooveNCS: [...] conduction studies are most usefultypically become abnormal 1st 2/2 [...] organization",
    "answer": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar GrooveNCS: **Motor::sensory / motor** conduction studies are most usefultypically become abnormal 1st 2/2 **somatotopic** organization",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647113269072,
    "question": "Cubital tunnel syndrome v.s. Retro Condylar Groove entrapmentmuscles involved include all ulnar n. innervated m’sSave for the [...], which may or may not be involved",
    "answer": "Cubital tunnel syndrome v.s. Retro Condylar Groove entrapmentmuscles involved include all ulnar n. innervated m’sSave for the **FCU**, which may or may not be involved",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647113458907,
    "question": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDX findings...EMG: abnormal activity in hand intrinsics [...] forearm muscles",
    "answer": "Cubital tunnel syndrome / Retro Condylar Groove EDX findings...EMG: abnormal activity in hand intrinsics **>::</=/> ** forearm muscles",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647114332678,
    "question": "GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation(1) [...] (2) [...] (3) [...](4) [...]",
    "answer": "GUYON’S CANAL clinical presentation(1) **deep palmar motor** (2) **deep palmar motor and hypothenar motor** (3) **evrything (proximal canal lesion)**(4) **only the sensory fiber to 4th and 5th**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647114682410,
    "question": "Guyons Canal EDX findings...SNAP: [...]CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal [...] (in conduction block)CV: [...] at the above elbow siteEMG: Abnormal activity in [...]",
    "answer": "Guyons Canal EDX findings...SNAP: **5th digit is abnormal, but DUC is normal**CMAP: Amplitude Abnormal **Wrist, B elbow, A elbow (OL/amp)::site** (in conduction block)CV: **normal::normal/abnormal** at the above elbow siteEMG: Abnormal activity in **ulnar innervated hand m's**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647118306827,
    "question": "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the [...]this is important* as the former requires [...]",
    "answer": "retrocondylar groove vs CUTS can be localized with the **inching technique**this is important* as the former requires **nerve transposition**",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647271368888,
    "question": "the most common cause of peripheral neuropathy wordlwide is [...]",
    "answer": "the most common cause of peripheral neuropathy wordlwide is **leprosy**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647566744208,
    "question": "In conduction block, EMG may reveal [...]",
    "answer": "In conduction block, EMG may reveal **decreased recruitment**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647566980413,
    "question": "Conduction Block To be considered significant, the drop in proximal amplitude should be more than [...]% of the distal amplitude.",
    "answer": "Conduction Block To be considered significant, the drop in proximal amplitude should be more than **20**% of the distal amplitude.",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647567132850,
    "question": "Nerve conduction studies in [...] [...] difference estimates the amount of [...] Usually, a [...]% difference is considered significantRecall that a significant drop in amp should be associated with [...]",
    "answer": "Nerve conduction studies in **axonal injuries::pathology** **side-to-side** difference estimates the amount of **axonal loss::same as 1** Usually, a **50**% difference is considered significantRecall that a significant drop in amp should be associated with **spontaneous activity**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647567326433,
    "question": "Axonal Injury Latencies and conduction velocities should [...] affected.",
    "answer": "Axonal Injury Latencies and conduction velocities should **not be::be/not be** affected.",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647567351542,
    "question": "Axonal Injury If [...] is present, the CMAP or SNAP amplitude will be unobtainable both proximal and distal to the lesion",
    "answer": "Axonal Injury If **neurotmesis::sunderland** is present, the CMAP or SNAP amplitude will be unobtainable both proximal and distal to the lesion",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1647819065544,
    "question": "4 Median n. FOREARM muscles(non-AIN m's)[...] [...][...][...]",
    "answer": "4 Median n. FOREARM muscles(non-AIN m's)**Pronator teres** **FCR****Palmaris longus****Flexor digitorum superficialis** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648316037027,
    "question": "Axonal Injury[...] and [...] should NOT be affectedUnless the [...] are affected",
    "answer": "Axonal Injury**O/P Latency** and **CV** should NOT be affectedUnless the **largest/fastest fibers::2** are affected",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648316417976,
    "question": "sensory loss in the forearm or arm [...] a feature of an ulnar nerve lesion",
    "answer": "sensory loss in the forearm or arm **is not::is / is not** a feature of an ulnar nerve lesion",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648316962748,
    "question": "“Clawing”—seen best with [...] lesions of median or ulnar nerves. Remaining extrinsic m. eg. [...] exaggerates the loss of the [...]",
    "answer": "“Clawing”—seen best with **distal** lesions of median or ulnar nerves. Remaining extrinsic m. eg. **flexor digitourm profundus** exaggerates the loss of the **lumbricals**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648317080437,
    "question": "Distortions of the hand median or ulnar n. Deficits less pronounced in [...] lesions; deficits present during [...]",
    "answer": "Distortions of the hand median or ulnar n. Deficits less pronounced in **proximal::distal/proximal** lesions; deficits present during **flexion::rest/flexion**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648319545747,
    "question": "Ulnar Motor study (ADM) MGA can be recognized...by a CMAP that is smaller with stimulation of the ulnar nerve at the [...] site than at the [...] siteproduces a [...] in the forearm (Preston and Shapiro, 2005)",
    "answer": "Ulnar Motor study (ADM) MGA can be recognized...by a CMAP that is smaller with stimulation of the ulnar nerve at the **B/A elbow** site than at the **wrist** siteproduces a **“pseudo-conduction block”** in the forearm (Preston and Shapiro, 2005)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648319999826,
    "question": "Ulnar Motor study MGA can be recognized...usually more apparent when recording from the [...] muscle, than [...] In such cases, the CMAP from the [...] muscle will be...[...] with stimulation of the median n. at the [...] compared the [...]",
    "answer": "Ulnar Motor study MGA can be recognized...usually more apparent when recording from the **FDI::site 1** muscle, than **ADM::site 2** In such cases, the CMAP from the **FDI::site 1** muscle will be...**larger** with stimulation of the median n. at the **elbow** compared the **wrist**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648320761994,
    "question": "Riches-Cannieu anastomosis (RCA) anastomosis in the [...] between the [...] and [...] severe [...] nerve injury in the arm = weak forearm flexors & sparing of thenar muscles. severe [...] nerve injury in the arm = unexpected weakness of all intrinsic hand muscles (including thenar)",
    "answer": "Riches-Cannieu anastomosis (RCA) anastomosis in the **palm** between the **ulnar deep motor branch** and **re-current median branch** severe **median** nerve injury in the arm = weak forearm flexors & sparing of thenar muscles. severe **ulnar** nerve injury in the arm = unexpected weakness of all intrinsic hand muscles (including thenar)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648321231503,
    "question": "Median Motor study (APB) suspect RCA if CMAP...[...] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: reduced or absent[...] n. stim at the wrist/elbow: present",
    "answer": "Median Motor study (APB) suspect RCA if CMAP...**median** n. stim at the wrist/elbow: reduced or absent**ulnar** n. stim at the wrist/elbow: present",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648385475248,
    "question": "Radial n. course[...] to the axillary artery. then, through the [...] (boarders made up of)under the [...] and between the [...] musclesalong the [...] before entering the anterior compartmentdescends between [...] medialy and [...] lateraly[...] to the [...] the n. branches into the [...] and [...] in the forearm it passes between superficial and deep heads of the [...] muscle aka the [...]",
    "answer": "Radial n. course**posterior** to the axillary artery. then, through the **triangular interval** (boarders made up of)under the **teres major** and between the **Lateral & Medial triceps::2** musclesalong the **spiral groove** before entering the anterior compartmentdescends between **brachialis** medialy and **brachioradialis** lateraly**anterior** to the **lateral epicondyle** the n. branches into the **PIN** and **superficial radial** in the forearm it passes between superficial and deep heads of the **supinator** muscle aka the **arcade of Fröhse** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648385937276,
    "question": "radial nerve cutaneous distributioninnervated above the spiral groove- [...]- [...]innervated below the spiral groove- [...]- [...]",
    "answer": "radial nerve cutaneous distributioninnervated above the spiral groove- **posterior cutaneous nerve of the arm**- **inferior lateral cutaneous nerve of the arm**innervated below the spiral groove- **posterior cutaneous nerve of forearm**- **superficial branch**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648386285281,
    "question": "Radial N. muscles of the armMuscles innervated above the spiral groove:[...][...]Muscles innervated below the spiral groove:[...][...]+/- [...]",
    "answer": "Radial N. muscles of the armMuscles innervated above the spiral groove:**Triceps brachii****Anconeus**Muscles innervated below the spiral groove:**Brachioradialis****ECR-L**+/- **ECR-B** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648386541230,
    "question": "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearmSuperficial [...][...][...][...]Deep/Snuff box muscles [...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Posterior Interosseus Nerve muscles of the forearmSuperficial **Supinator****Extensor digitorum (communus)****Extensor digiti minimi (EDM)****Extensor carpi ulnaris (ECU)**Deep/Snuff box muscles **Abductor pollicis longus (APL)****Extensor pollicis longus (EPL)****Extensor pollicis brevis (EPB)****Extensor indicis proprius (EIP)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648386963408,
    "question": "[...] aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the [...] of the brachial plexus (rare)",
    "answer": "**CRUTCH PALSY** aka radial injury at the axilla can involve the **posterior cord** of the brachial plexus (rare)",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648387116390,
    "question": "crutch palsy clincial presentationmay c/o weakness in [...], Sensation may be decreased over the [...]",
    "answer": "crutch palsy clincial presentationmay c/o weakness in **all radial n. innervated m.**, Sensation may be decreased over the **posterior arm, forearm, and hand**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648387496494,
    "question": "crutch palsy EDX findings CMAP Cases associated with axonal loss and Wallerian degeneration show [...] at [...]Cases associated with meylin loss and Conduction block show [...] at [...] SNAP [...] response is [...] in cases of axonal loss EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",
    "answer": "crutch palsy EDX findings CMAP Cases associated with axonal loss and Wallerian degeneration show **low amplitudes** at **all 3 stim sites**Cases associated with meylin loss and Conduction block show **Nl. amplitudes** at **all 3 stim sites** SNAP **superficial radial sensory** response is **reduced in amplitude/absent** in cases of axonal loss EMGAbnormal activity in **all radial n. muscles +/- posterior cord muscles::2 categories**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648387570248,
    "question": "radial n. Injury at the spiral-groove is also known as [...] palsy or [...] palsy",
    "answer": "radial n. Injury at the spiral-groove is also known as **Saturday night** palsy or **honeymooner’s** palsy",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648387937920,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-grooveclinical presentationweakness of [...], [...], [...], and [...]There is preservation of [...] Sensory deficits may occur in the [...]",
    "answer": "Radial n. injury at spiral-grooveclinical presentationweakness of **elbow flexion (BR)**, **supination**, **wrist extension (ECR-L/B, ECU)**, and **finger extension (EDC)**There is preservation of **elbow extension (triceps, anconeus)** Sensory deficits may occur in the **dorsal aspect hand and forearm** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648388439389,
    "question": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings:NCS:CMAP: normal at [...] in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at [...] in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be [...] in [...]EMG: Abnormal activity in [...]",
    "answer": "Radial n. injury at spiral-groove EDX findings:NCS:CMAP: normal at **all 3 sites::stim site** in conduction block CMAP: abnormal at **all 3 sites::stim site** in wallerian degeneration superficial radial sensory response could be **normal** in **demyelination**EMG: Abnormal activity in **all radial n. except the triceps and anconeus::m.** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648388620818,
    "question": "Differential Diagnosis of a Wrist Drop[...][...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Differential Diagnosis of a Wrist Drop**Central: SCI/TBI/CVA, etc.****Radiculopathy: C6 or C7::2****Plexopathy: Posterior cord, upper / middle trunk::3****Mononeuropathy: PIN, radial nerve::2****Diffuse polyneuropathy: Lead**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648388915714,
    "question": "[...] radial nerve can be entrapped between the [...]c/o [...] pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic [...]",
    "answer": "**RADIAL TUNNEL SYNDROME** radial nerve can be entrapped between the **brachialis and BR::2**c/o **lateral/dorsal proximal forearm** pain that worsens with activity, which can mimic **lateral epicondylitis**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648389241764,
    "question": "Radial Tunnel syndrome NCS will demonstrate [...] EMG will demonstrate [...]",
    "answer": "Radial Tunnel syndrome NCS will demonstrate **typically no findings** EMG will demonstrate **typically no findings**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648390000301,
    "question": "[...]: radial n. injured at the [...] of the supinatorpresents with [...] weakness of all the [...]they will display weakness with only [...] and will show a [...] deviated wrist",
    "answer": "**posterior interosseous syndrome**: radial n. injured at the **Arcade of Frohse** of the supinatorpresents with **painless*::painful/painless** weakness of all the **PIN innervated m::same**they will display weakness with only **finger/thumb extension::2** and will show a **radial (ECU weak. ECR intact)** deviated wrist",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1648390658768,
    "question": "Posterior interosseous syndrome EDX findings:NCS: superfical radial sensory [...] SNAP. in conduction block [...] radial CMAP when recording over PIN innervated muscles (EIP)EMG:Abnormal in +/- supinator and all PIN muscles.[...] are always spared",
    "answer": "Posterior interosseous syndrome EDX findings:NCS: superfical radial sensory **Normal::normal/abnormal** SNAP. in conduction block **Abnormal::normal/abnormal** radial CMAP when recording over PIN innervated muscles (EIP)EMG:Abnormal in +/- supinator and all PIN muscles.**triceps, anconeus, BR, ECR-L, and ECR-B::5** are always spared (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1649363201236,
    "question": "Superficial radial neuropathy: also known as [...] or [...] also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy",
    "answer": "Superficial radial neuropathy: also known as **Wartenberg syndrome::eponym** or **cheiralgia paresthetica** also known informally as wristwatch syndrome or handcuff palsy",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1649363528230,
    "question": "Hand-cuff palsy EDX findings: Normal/AbnormalNCS: superfical radial nerve SNAP: [...] radial nerve CMAP: [...] EMG: [...]",
    "answer": "Hand-cuff palsy EDX findings: Normal/AbnormalNCS: superfical radial nerve SNAP: **Abnormal** radial nerve CMAP: **Normal** EMG: **Normal**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1649365335683,
    "question": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located proximal to the DRGCMAP: [...]",
    "answer": "Radiculopathy SNAP: Normal if the lesion is located proximal to the DRGCMAP: **Normal or reduced amplitude::2**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1649688608541,
    "question": "Note that a mean of [...]-waves can be used as a surrogate for one H-reflex",
    "answer": "Note that a mean of **10 F**-waves can be used as a surrogate for one H-reflex",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650035365488,
    "question": "Musculocutaneous n. course arises from the lateral cord of the brachial plexus near the lower border of [...] muscle. downward to pierce the [...] muscle, which it innervates. in the upper arm, travels between the [...] muscles at the antecubital fossa, it pierces deep fascia lateral to the [...] and becomes the LAC",
    "answer": "Musculocutaneous n. course arises from the lateral cord of the brachial plexus near the lower border of **pectoralis minor** muscle. downward to pierce the **coracobrachialis** muscle, which it innervates. in the upper arm, travels between the **brachialis and biceps::2** muscles at the antecubital fossa, it pierces deep fascia lateral to the **biceps tendon** and becomes the LAC",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650035649219,
    "question": "musculocutaneous nerve. innervates ARM 3 muscles [...][...][...]FOREARM 1 cutaneous sensory [...]",
    "answer": "musculocutaneous nerve. innervates ARM 3 muscles **Coracobrachialis****Biceps brachii****Brachialis (also radial nerve)**FOREARM 1 cutaneous sensory **lateral antebrachial cutaneous (LAC)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650036460113,
    "question": "MUSCULOCUTANEOUS MONO-NEUROPATHYIn General: Injury to the [...] portion of the nerve is more common than to the [...] portion",
    "answer": "MUSCULOCUTANEOUS MONO-NEUROPATHYIn General: Injury to the **distal::proximal/distal** portion of the nerve is more common than to the **proximal::proximal/distal** portion",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650036632531,
    "question": "{{c1::median SNAP {from the thumb} and superficial radial SNAP::2 EDx}} should be performed to distinguish musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy from upper trunk lesion",
    "answer": "{{c1::median SNAP {from the thumb} and superficial radial SNAP::2 EDx}} should be performed to distinguish musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy from upper trunk lesion",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "definition"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650036756464,
    "question": "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy clinical pres. patient may complain of [...] weakness and abnormal sensation over the [...]",
    "answer": "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropathy clinical pres. patient may complain of **elbow flexion** weakness and abnormal sensation over the **lateral forearm**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650037069663,
    "question": "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal SNAP in the [...]Abnormal CMAP to the [...]EMG:Abnormal activity in the [...]",
    "answer": "Musculocutaneous mono-neuropahty EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal SNAP in the **LAC**Abnormal CMAP to the **biceps brachii**EMG:Abnormal activity in the **biceps brachii** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650038357953,
    "question": "Axillary n. Course: descends posterior to the [...] artery and anterior to the [...] muscle. it then curves posteriorly through the [...] with the posterior circumflex artery. As the nerve emerges, it divides into anterior and posterior terminal divisions.",
    "answer": "Axillary n. Course: descends posterior to the **axillary** artery and anterior to the **subscapularis** muscle. it then curves posteriorly through the **quadrangular space** with the posterior circumflex artery. As the nerve emerges, it divides into anterior and posterior terminal divisions.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650038451864,
    "question": "Axillary n. innervates 3 [...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Axillary n. innervates 3 **Teres minor****Deltoid****Upper lateral cutaneous nerve::sensory** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650038778690,
    "question": "Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings:NCS:SNAP [...]CMAP: [...] EMG:Abnormal activity in the [...] muscles",
    "answer": "Axillary mono-neuropathy EDX findings:NCS:SNAP **not available**CMAP: **Abnormal (not done)** EMG:Abnormal activity in the **deltoid and teres minor::2** muscles (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650039428954,
    "question": "suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the [...] which it branches off then passes the [...] of the neck and runs beneath the [...] to the superior margin of the scapula.It runs through the [...], to innervate the [...] The nerve then wraps around the [...], to innervate the [...]",
    "answer": "suprascapular nerve. course originate from the C5 and C6 spinal nerve roots and contributes to the **upper trunk::plexus** which it branches off then passes the **posterior triangle** of the neck and runs beneath the **trapezius** to the superior margin of the scapula.It runs through the **suprascapular notch**, to innervate the **supraspinatus** The nerve then wraps around the **spinoglenoid notch**, to innervate the **infraspinatus** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650039617011,
    "question": "SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHYThis is the only peripheral nerve injury at the [...] level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in [...]",
    "answer": "SUPRASCAPULAR NEUROPATHYThis is the only peripheral nerve injury at the **trunk** level. It is the most commonly involved nerve in **neuralgic amyotrophy**",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650039841620,
    "question": "Suprascapular neuropathy clinical pres.proximal injury results in weakness in both [...] and [...] Nerve injury at the spinoglenoid notch will result in weakness [...]",
    "answer": "Suprascapular neuropathy clinical pres.proximal injury results in weakness in both **shoulder abduction (SS)** and **external rotation (IS)** Nerve injury at the spinoglenoid notch will result in weakness **only in external rotation (IS)**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650040083342,
    "question": "Long thoracic n.runs distally along the thoracic wall to innervate the [...]",
    "answer": "Long thoracic n.runs distally along the thoracic wall to innervate the **serratus anterior**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650040439910,
    "question": "2 main types of shoulder winging. EDx findings...Medial winging: EMG findings in [...] Lateral winging: EMG findings in [...]",
    "answer": "2 main types of shoulder winging. EDx findings...Medial winging: EMG findings in **serratus anterior** Lateral winging: EMG findings in **trapezius (&SCM)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1650040991808,
    "question": "Treatment of serratus anterior injury/injury to the long thoracic nerve: same 2 for both(a) acute stage, pain reduction and ROM exercise; (b) intermediate stage, passive stretching of the [...], [...], and pectoralis minor; (c) late stage, strengthening exercise of all shoulder girdle muscles, including the trapezius.Treatment of trapezius palsy/injury to the spinal accessory nerve: Will involve physical therapy to adequately strengthen adjacent muscle groups, including [...] and [...].Surgical repair with a [...] is recommended if the patient fails conservative treatment.",
    "answer": "Treatment of serratus anterior injury/injury to the long thoracic nerve: same 2 for both(a) acute stage, pain reduction and ROM exercise; (b) intermediate stage, passive stretching of the **rhomboids**, **levator scapulae**, and pectoralis minor; (c) late stage, strengthening exercise of all shoulder girdle muscles, including the trapezius.Treatment of trapezius palsy/injury to the spinal accessory nerve: Will involve physical therapy to adequately strengthen adjacent muscle groups, including **rhomboids** and **levator scapulae**.Surgical repair with a **dynamic muscle transfer** is recommended if the patient fails conservative treatment.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1651175503251,
    "question": "Motor unit [...] is a better measure of pathology",
    "answer": "Motor unit **duration::polyphasicity/duration** is a better measure of pathology",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1651175806279,
    "question": "Abnormal spontaneous potentials are usually only found in [...]",
    "answer": "Abnormal spontaneous potentials are usually only found in **axonal injury::axon/myelin injury**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1654356207919,
    "question": "[...] injury may generate spontaneous activity",
    "answer": "**BOTH Muscle & Nerve::muscle/nerve** injury may generate spontaneous activity",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657459282046,
    "question": "lateral femoral cutaneous n.pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the [...] and [...] nerve roots from the [...] division of the lumbar plexus",
    "answer": "lateral femoral cutaneous n.pure sensory nerve fibers originate from the **L2** and **L3** nerve roots from the **posterior** division of the lumbar plexus",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657459774010,
    "question": "lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka [...]Etiology1.) [...]2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, [...], infection, [...] 3.) [...]",
    "answer": "lateral femoral cutaneous neuropathy aka **meralgia paresthetica**Etiology1.) **compression**2.) medical cuases: Diabetes, **tumor**, infection, **weight gain/loss** 3.) **Iatrogenic::category**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657460002285,
    "question": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the [...] toward the [...]It passes underneath the [...] to provide sensation to the lateral thigh",
    "answer": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve course pass over the **iliacus::m.** toward the **anterior iliac spine**It passes underneath the **inguinal ligament** to provide sensation to the lateral thigh (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657460214376,
    "question": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve. clinical pres.patient may report sensory complaints in the lateral thigh, including pain, numbness, burning, or a dull ache, exacerbated by [...] and [...]",
    "answer": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve. clinical pres.patient may report sensory complaints in the lateral thigh, including pain, numbness, burning, or a dull ache, exacerbated by **hip extension/flexion** and **prolonged sitting**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657460357643,
    "question": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...] CMAP: [...]EMG[...]",
    "answer": "lateral femoral cutaneous nerve, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal lateral femoral cutaneous nerve (not typically done)** CMAP: **not available**EMG**not available**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657461725787,
    "question": "Femoral n. innervates (motor)[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Femoral n. innervates (motor)**Iliacus* (illiopsoas)****Pectineus (1/2)****Sartorius****Quadriceps m. x4::category** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657462196164,
    "question": "Sensory Femoral n. innervates Iliacus (illiopsoas)Pectineus (1/2)Anterior BranchSartorius[...][...]Posterior Branch[...][...]Quadriceps m. x4",
    "answer": "Sensory Femoral n. innervates Iliacus (illiopsoas)Pectineus (1/2)Anterior BranchSartorius**intermediate cutaneous nerve of the thigh::Sensory****medial cutaneous nerve of the thigh::Sensory**Posterior Branch**Saphenous nerve::Sensory****infra-patellar branch of saphenous::Sensory**Quadriceps m. x4 (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657463547131,
    "question": "FEMORAL NERVE course: lumbar plexus, 2, 3, 4 ventral rami. within the substance of the [...]. emerges in a groove between this muscle and the [...] and descends under the [...] beneath which, a branch courses behind the [...] to innervate the [...]in the [...], n. lies on the iliacus m. lateral to the [...]About [...] cm distal, it divides into 2 cutaneous n's The [...] divides to the sartorius and two cutaneous branches (intermediate and medial cutaneous n's of thigh) The [...] divides into the saphenous branch and rectus branches",
    "answer": "FEMORAL NERVE course: lumbar plexus, 2, 3, 4 ventral rami. within the substance of the **psoas major**. emerges in a groove between this muscle and the **iliacus** and descends under the **inguinal ligament** beneath which, a branch courses behind the **femoral sheath** to innervate the **pectineus m.**in the **femoral triangle**, n. lies on the iliacus m. lateral to the **femoral artery**About **4** cm distal, it divides into 2 cutaneous n's The **anterior division** divides to the sartorius and two cutaneous branches (intermediate and medial cutaneous n's of thigh) The **posterior division** divides into the saphenous branch and rectus branches (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657464883811,
    "question": "saphenous nerve course, a [...] nerve femoral n --> [...] division --> saphenous n. travels through the [...]descends to the [...], where it becomes [...], and joins the saphenous v.provides sensation to the skin of the [...]",
    "answer": "saphenous nerve course, a **pure sensory::motor/sensory/mixed** nerve femoral n --> **posterior** division --> saphenous n. travels through the **adductor canal**descends to the **knee**, where it becomes **subcutaneous**, and joins the saphenous v.provides sensation to the skin of the **medial leg, ankle, and foot::3**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657466031956,
    "question": "Femoral Neuropathy, Etiology:compression/trauma [...] tumor entrapped at inguinal ligamentfractureiatrogenic (most common)[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Femoral Neuropathy, Etiology:compression/trauma **retroperitoneal hemmorhage/ psoas hematoma::2** tumor entrapped at inguinal ligamentfractureiatrogenic (most common)**positioning during surgery (eg. dorsal lithotomy)****cardiac catherization****THA****femoral/inguinal hernia repair**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657466279957,
    "question": "Femoral Neuropathyclinical presentation:patient may complain of weakness of [...][...] weakness is noted with injuries occurring above the [...]decreased sensation over the [...], [...], and [...] [...] reflex is reduced or absent",
    "answer": "Femoral Neuropathyclinical presentation:patient may complain of weakness of **knee extension****Hip flexion** weakness is noted with injuries occurring above the **inguinal ligament**decreased sensation over the **anterior thigh**, **medial thigh**, and **medial leg** **patellar tendon** reflex is reduced or absent",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657466862912,
    "question": "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal [...]Abnormal [...]EMG:- Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. [...]) to r/o [...] involvement",
    "answer": "Femoral Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCS:Abnormal **saphenous nerve SNAP**Abnormal **rectus femoris CMAP**EMG:- Abnormal activity in femoral n. innervated m's - if abnl, then study other m's (eg. **hamstrings, gluts, adductor::1ex.**) to r/o **plexus/root::2** involvement (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657467106448,
    "question": "[...] is the most common cause of femoral neuropathy",
    "answer": "**Diabetic amyotrophy** is the most common cause of femoral neuropathy",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657467185148,
    "question": "[...] is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathiesit is also known as a [...] neuropathy",
    "answer": "**Diabetic amyotrophy** is a proximal diabetic neuropathy distinct from other types of distal diabetic peripheral neuropathiesit is also known as a **lumbo-sacral radiculo-plexus::\"4-names\"** neuropathy",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657467276166,
    "question": "exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal [...]. The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting [...] injury and perivascular infiltrateamyotrophy has been noted to occur after [...]",
    "answer": "exact cause of diabetic amyotrophy is unknown believed to result from a multifocal **immune-mediated microvasculitis::2 names**. The nerve is believed to be injured from an abnormality of the vaso-nervorum due to diabetes mellitus. Nerve biopsy shows multifocal nerve fiber loss suggesting **ischemic** injury and perivascular infiltrateamyotrophy has been noted to occur after **marked weight loss::pt characteristic**",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657468292088,
    "question": "diabetic amyotrophy typically affects (epidimiology)[...]usually [...][...]",
    "answer": "diabetic amyotrophy typically affects (epidimiology)**males**usually **> 50 yo****type 2 DM**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657468621213,
    "question": "diabetic amyotrophyClinical presentation:begins with [...] in the [...] or [...]commonly spreads to the [...] within [...] Patients then develops [...] and [...] of the proximal > distal lower extremity musculature",
    "answer": "diabetic amyotrophyClinical presentation:begins with **severe unilateral pain** in the **lumbar region** or **proximal lower extremity**commonly spreads to the **contralateral side** within **weeks to months::time range** Patients then develops **weakness** and **atrophy** of the proximal > distal lower extremity musculature",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657468787620,
    "question": "diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings:NCS:[...] SNAP saphenous*[...] CMAP rectusEMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), [...]iliopsoas[...]",
    "answer": "diabetic amyotrophy EDX findings:NCS:**Abnormal** SNAP saphenous***Abnormal** CMAP rectusEMG (Abnormal activity): femoral innervated muscles (±), **adductors**iliopsoas**paraspinals** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657976050421,
    "question": "SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHYEtiologycan be entrapped in the [...] (aka [...]) or between the [...] and [...]iatrogenic trauma, including [...] or [...]",
    "answer": "SAPHENOUS NEUROPATHYEtiologycan be entrapped in the **hip adductor canal** (aka **Hunter’s canal**) or between the **sartorius** and **gracilis**iatrogenic trauma, including **knee arthroscopy/meniscectomy** or **catheterization/thrombectomy**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657976454410,
    "question": "Saphenous Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...] EMGfemoral nerve innervated muscles: [...]",
    "answer": "Saphenous Neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal saphenous nerve**CMAP: **Normal** EMGfemoral nerve innervated muscles: **Normal**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657978130178,
    "question": "Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the [...], and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral ramiexits the pelvis through the [...] below the [...] musclebetween the [...] and [...]. (bony landmarks)the nerve is deep to the [...] m. and [...] m.down the midline of the thigh closely related to the [...]travels as one unit up to the [...], where it splits into the peroneal (fibular) division and tibial division",
    "answer": "Sciatic Nerve, course (tibial & peroneal) L4, L5 roots from the **lumbosacral trunk**, and the 1st, 2nd, and 3rd sacral ventral ramiexits the pelvis through the **greater sciatic foramen** below the **piriformis** musclebetween the **lesser trochanter** and **ischial tuberosity**. (bony landmarks)the nerve is deep to the **gluteus maximus::pelvis** m. and **biceps femoris::thigh** m.down the midline of the thigh closely related to the **shaft of the femur**travels as one unit up to the **popliteal fossa**, where it splits into the peroneal (fibular) division and tibial division (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657978403942,
    "question": "Sciatic nerve muscle innervation in the thighperoneal (fibular) division [...]tibial division [...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Sciatic nerve muscle innervation in the thighperoneal (fibular) division **Short head biceps femoris**tibial division **Long head biceps femoris****Semitendinosus****Semimembranosus****Adductor magnus (also obturator n.)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657978722014,
    "question": "the [...] division makes up the outer two-thirds of the sciatic nerve proper",
    "answer": "the **peroneal** division makes up the outer two-thirds of the sciatic nerve proper",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657978979780,
    "question": "SCIATIC NEUROPATHYEtiology:[...][...][...]hematoma / tumor penetrating woundsgravid uterus",
    "answer": "SCIATIC NEUROPATHYEtiology:**hip dislocation / fx****THA****IM injection**hematoma / tumor penetrating woundsgravid uterus",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657979081889,
    "question": "[...] is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the [...] portion of the nerve",
    "answer": "**Piriformis syndrome** is an uncommon type of compressive sciatic neuropathy at the pelvic outlet that mainly affects the **peroneal (fibular)** portion of the nerve",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657983199640,
    "question": "Sciatic neuropathyClinical presentation:primarily presents as weakness of [...] and [...]numbness occurs over the [...] and the [...]The [...] and [...] may be abnormal (physical examination)",
    "answer": "Sciatic neuropathyClinical presentation:primarily presents as weakness of **knee flexion** and **muscles of the peroneal (foot drop) and tibial nerves* (plantar flexion)**numbness occurs over the **lateral leg** and the **entire foot**The **lateral hamstring** and **Achilles reflexes** may be abnormal (physical examination)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657983880693,
    "question": "Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...] CMAP: Abnormal [...] EMGAbnormal activity in [...]Normal activity in [...] and [...] absent or delayed [...]",
    "answer": "Sciatic neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal ** superficial peroneal (fibular) and sural sensory** CMAP: Abnormal **tibial and comm. peroneal (fibular) motor studies** EMGAbnormal activity in **all sciatic innervated musculature 1.) hamstrings (eg. biceps femoris s/l + semi m/t), 2.) tibial n. (eg. gastroc + tib post), and 3.) c. peroneal n. (tib ant. + fib brevis/long)**Normal activity in **gluteus medius (r/o plexopathy)** and **lumbar paraspinals (r/o radiculopathy)** absent or delayed **H-reflex** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1657984061306,
    "question": "[...] portion of the sciatic nerve is more vulnerable to injury",
    "answer": "**peroneal (fibular)** portion of the sciatic nerve is more vulnerable to injury",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658084858130,
    "question": "Tibial nerve course descends along the popliteal fossa to the distal border of the [...] muscle, superficial to it proximally, it is positioned [...] to the popliteal vessels, before crossing to the opposite side passes anterior to the [...] deep to the [...] muscle, to enter the leg in the distal one-third of the leg it is covered only by skin and fascia, sometimes overlapped by the [...]It reaches the [...], ending under the [...]where it divides into medial and lateral [...] nerves",
    "answer": "Tibial nerve course descends along the popliteal fossa to the distal border of the **popliteus** muscle, superficial to it proximally, it is positioned **lateral::side** to the popliteal vessels, before crossing to the opposite side passes anterior to the **aponeurotic arch::landmark** deep to the **soleus** muscle, to enter the leg in the distal one-third of the leg it is covered only by skin and fascia, sometimes overlapped by the **flexor hallucis longus**It reaches the **medial malleolus::bony structure**, ending under the **flexor retinaculum**where it divides into medial and lateral **plantar** nerves (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658085115905,
    "question": "sural nerve, course [...] is joined by the [...], a branch of the [...] nerve descends along the calf and [...] border of the [...] to the region between the [...] and the [...].",
    "answer": "sural nerve, course **medial sural** is joined by the **sural communicating**, a branch of the **common peroneal** nerve descends along the calf and **lateral::side** border of the **Achilles tendon::anatomical landmark** to the region between the **lateral malleolus** and the **calcaneus**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658085647281,
    "question": "sural nerve cutaneous It supplies the [...] and [...] skin of the distal [...] of the leg, the skin overlying the [...] [...], and the [...] aspect of the [...] and [...] the [...] branch supplies the skin of the [...]",
    "answer": "sural nerve cutaneous It supplies the **posterior** and **lateral** skin of the distal **third** of the leg, the skin overlying the **lateral** **malleolus**, and the **lateral** aspect of the **foot** and **little toe** the **medial calcaneal** branch supplies the skin of the **medial heel**",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658086162737,
    "question": "Tibial N. innervatesSuperficial/proximal[...][...][...][...]Deep/distal[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Tibial N. innervatesSuperficial/proximal**Popliteus****Plantaris****Gastrocnemius****Soleus**Deep/distal**Tibialis posterior (TP)****Flexor digitorum longus (FDL)****Flexor hallucis longus (FHL)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658086625234,
    "question": "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel)Medial plantar nerve[...][...][...][...]Sensory branchLateral plantar nerve[...][...][...][...][...][...]Sensory branchesCalcaneal nerveSensory branch",
    "answer": "Tibial nerve innervates m. (distal to tarsal tunnel)Medial plantar nerve**Abductor hallucis****Flexor hallucis brevis****Flexor digitorum brevis****1st Lumbrical**Sensory branchLateral plantar nerve**Lumbricals****Interossei****Quadratus plantae****Abductor digiti minimi****Flexor digiti minimi****Adductor hallucis**Sensory branchesCalcaneal nerveSensory branch (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658086773238,
    "question": "[...]: tibial n. injured by compression under the flexor retinaculum in the medial ankle",
    "answer": "**tarsal tunnel sndrome**: tibial n. injured by compression under the flexor retinaculum in the medial ankle",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658087179287,
    "question": "Tarsal tunnel syndromeClinical presentationInvolves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to [...]pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial [...] area and entire [...]It is reproduced by [...]positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited",
    "answer": "Tarsal tunnel syndromeClinical presentationInvolves all muscles innervated by the tibial nerve distal to the tarsal tunnel. thus patient may complain of symptoms related to **intrinsic foot weakness**pain, numbness, and paresthesias may involve the medial **Perimalleolar** area and entire **sole**It is reproduced by **ankle inversion**positive Tinel’s sign at the medial ankle may be elicited",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658087691769,
    "question": "Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]. Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...]EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",
    "answer": "Tarsal tunnel, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal **medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same**. Normal **calcaneal nerve**CMAP: Abnormal **medial and lateral plantar nerve::2 same**EMGAbnormal activity in **all tibial n. foot muscles (entire sole of foot)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658087942869,
    "question": "contents of the Tarsal tunnel[...][...] [...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "contents of the Tarsal tunnel**Tibialis Posterior****flexor Digitorum longus** **Post. Tib A.****Post. Tib V.****Tibial N.****Flexor Hallucis longus** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658698599790,
    "question": "Common peroneal n. course curves laterally around the [...] of the [...], passing through a [...] opening in the [...] muscle. deep peroneal n. passes in between the [...] m. and [...] m.at the ankle, divides into the [...] branch to supply the extensor digitorum brevis and the [...] branch to the 1st interspace superficial peroneal n. runs between the [...] and [...] musclesand emerges at lower [...] of the leg, where it divides into lateral and medial terminal which are sensory",
    "answer": "Common peroneal n. course curves laterally around the **neck** of the **fibula**, passing through a **fibro-osseous** opening in the **peroneus longus** muscle. deep peroneal n. passes in between the **extensor digitorum longus** m. and **tibialis anterior** m.at the ankle, divides into the **lateral terminal** branch to supply the extensor digitorum brevis and the **medial terminal** branch to the 1st interspace superficial peroneal n. runs between the **peroneus longus** and **extensor digitorum longus** musclesand emerges at lower **1/3** of the leg, where it divides into lateral and medial terminal which are sensory (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658699763997,
    "question": "Common peroneal cutaneous It gives off 2 cutaneous branches, the [...] nerve aka [...] this supplies the skin of the [...] aspects of the legthe [...] nerve descends medially to join the [...] to become the sural nervebranches in the fossa also supply the [...]",
    "answer": "Common peroneal cutaneous It gives off 2 cutaneous branches, the **lateral sural** nerve aka **lateral cutaneous nerve of the calf** this supplies the skin of the **anterior, lateral** aspects of the legthe **sural communicating** nerve descends medially to join the **medial sural** to become the sural nervebranches in the fossa also supply the **knee joint**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658700232615,
    "question": "Superficial Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates: (2 motor 2 sensory)[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Superficial Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates: (2 motor 2 sensory)**Peroneus longus****Peroneus brevis****Medial cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum)****Lateral cutaneous nerve (foot dorsum)** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658700541562,
    "question": "Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates:Leg[...][...][...]Foot[...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Deep Peroneal (Fibular) Nerve innervates:Leg**Tibialis Anterior****Extensor Digitorum Longus****Extensor Hallucis Longus**Foot**Peroneus tertius****Extensor Digitorum Brevis****First dorsal interossei****Dorsal digital cutaneous n. (1st Web-space)::sensory** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658701328163,
    "question": "Peroneal nerve injury Etiology[...][...][...][...][...]common[...] [...]",
    "answer": "Peroneal nerve injury Etiology**prolonged leg crossing****rapid weight loss (slimmer's paralysis)****positioning during surgery****cast application/tight boots (ski-boot palsy)****prolonged squatting position (strawberry pickers’ palsy)**common**metabolic disorders (diabetes, etoh use, etc.)** **trauma (to the knee or fibula)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658701692372,
    "question": "Comm. Peroneal n. injury Clinical presentation There is weakness of [...] and [...] as well a commonly weakness of [...] Loss of sensation or numbness commonly occurs over the [...] and [...][...] may be noted at the fibular head",
    "answer": "Comm. Peroneal n. injury Clinical presentation There is weakness of **foot dorsiflexion** and **extension of the toes** as well a commonly weakness of **foot eversion** Loss of sensation or numbness commonly occurs over the **antero-lateral leg** and **entire dorsum of foot****Tinel’s sign** may be noted at the fibular head",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658702063609,
    "question": "Weakness of only the ankle dorsiflexors and [...] helps to clinically differentiate a [...] nerve injury from a/an: [...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Weakness of only the ankle dorsiflexors and **ankle evertors** helps to clinically differentiate a **common peroneal (fibular)** nerve injury from a/an: **L5 radiculopathy****Lumbar Plexopathy****Sciatic Neuropathy**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658703565315,
    "question": "Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP Abnormal [...] Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...] Normal at [...] EMGAbnormal activity muscles innervated by the [...]ex. [...]ex. [...] Normal activity in [...]as well as [...]+ add on [...](not glut med, or paraspinals)",
    "answer": "Common peroneal neuropathy EDX findings:NCSSNAP Abnormal **superficial peroneal (fibular)** Normal **Sural nerve**CMAP: Abnormal **above fibular head::conduction block** Normal at **ankle and below fibular head::conduction block** EMGAbnormal activity muscles innervated by the ** both superficial and deep peroneal nerves::2**ex. **Tibialis Anterior, extensor hallucis longus**ex. **Peroneus longus/brevis** Normal activity in **biceps femoris-short (sciatic nerve, peroneal (fibular) division \"proximal extent\")::r/o**as well as **Gastroc (S1, S2) [r/o sciatic involvement]::r/o**+ add on **Tibialis posterior (L5, S1) [r/o L5 radic]::r/o**(not glut med, or paraspinals) (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658703663248,
    "question": "Common peroneal nerve NCSthe [...] can be used if the EDB is atrophied",
    "answer": "Common peroneal nerve NCSthe **TA** can be used if the EDB is atrophied",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658704389962,
    "question": "If... EMG is abnormal in the common peroneal nerve m's [ie. Tib. Ant. & Peroneus Longus] then... you must study the [...] to [...] of the lesion",
    "answer": "If... EMG is abnormal in the common peroneal nerve m's [ie. Tib. Ant. & Peroneus Longus] then... you must study the **biceps femoris (short head)** to **define proximal extent** of the lesion (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658704898777,
    "question": "DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYAKA [...] refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the [...] of the ankle",
    "answer": "DEEP PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYAKA **anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome** refers to entrapment of the deep peroneal (fibular) nerve under the **inferior extensor retinaculum** of the ankle",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658705111733,
    "question": "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentationmay have weakness, and atrophy of the [...] numbness and paresthesias in the [...] Pain may be located over the [...] that is relieved with [...]",
    "answer": "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome clinical presentationmay have weakness, and atrophy of the **EDB** numbness and paresthesias in the **1st / 2nd web space** Pain may be located over the **dorsum of the foot** that is relieved with **motion**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658705500859,
    "question": "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]Normal [...]CMAP: Abnormal [...] (Conduction Block)EMGAbnormal activity in [...]",
    "answer": "anterior tarsal tunnel syndrome EDX findings:NCSSNAP: Abnormal **deep peroneal (fibular) (Abnormal findings to the first web space [Never seen this done])**Normal **superficial peroneal**CMAP: Abnormal **common peroneal (fibular) Motor ALL sites (Ankle & a/b fib)** (Conduction Block)EMGAbnormal activity in **deep peroneal (fibular) innervated muscles below the ankle (ie EDB)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658706239543,
    "question": "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYClinical presentation:c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in [...] and [...] except for the [...] [...] weakness can also be noted",
    "answer": "SUPERFICIAL PERONEAL (FIBULAR) NEUROPATHYClinical presentation:c/o of pain, numbness, and/or paresthesias or loss of sensation in **distal anterolateral calf** and **dorsal foot** except for the **1st webspace** **Foot eversion** weakness can also be noted",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1658706482385,
    "question": "superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findingsNCSSNAP: Abnormal [...]Normal [...]CMAP: Normal [...][...]EMGAbnormal activity in [...]normal findings in [...]",
    "answer": "superficial peroneal neuropathy EDX findingsNCSSNAP: Abnormal **superficial peroneal (fibular) sensory**Normal **sural sensory**CMAP: Normal **common peroneal Motor (from deep fib)****Tibial Motor (Superficial peroneal motor, not available)**EMGAbnormal activity in **peroneus longus and/or peroneus brevis**normal findings in **deep peroneal (fibular) nerve innervated muscles ie Tib. Ant.** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660572795623,
    "question": "[...] nerve: anomalous branch from the [...] nerve that travels [...] to the [...] to innervate some or all of the [...]",
    "answer": "**accessory peroneal (fibular)** nerve: anomalous branch from the **superficial peroneal (fibular)** nerve that travels **posterior** to the **lateral malleolus** to innervate some or all of the **extensor digitorum brevis (EDB)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660573274951,
    "question": "accessory deep peroneal nerve can be recognized by a CMAP that is [...] with stimulation of the peroneal nerve at [...] site than at the [...] site",
    "answer": "accessory deep peroneal nerve can be recognized by a CMAP that is **larger** with stimulation of the peroneal nerve at **b/a knee** site than at the **ankle** site",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660573374270,
    "question": "accessory peroneal (fibular) n.can be confirmed by [...]",
    "answer": "accessory peroneal (fibular) n.can be confirmed by **stimulating posterior to the lateral malleolus**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660573872784,
    "question": "in a patient with a dominant accessory deep peroneal nerve and common peroneal neuropathy at the fibular head due to conduction block, stimulation of the peroneal n. at the [...] and [...] site may fail to elicit a CMAPwhereas...stimulation of the peroneal n. at the [...] may elicit the only recordable motor response",
    "answer": "in a patient with a dominant accessory deep peroneal nerve and common peroneal neuropathy at the fibular head due to conduction block, stimulation of the peroneal n. at the **ankle** and **above the knee** site may fail to elicit a CMAPwhereas...stimulation of the peroneal n. at the **below the knee** may elicit the only recordable motor response",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660574107712,
    "question": "accessory peroneal n.with this anomalous innervation... the EDB can be spared with a [...] nerve injury",
    "answer": "accessory peroneal n.with this anomalous innervation... the EDB can be spared with a **deep peroneal (aka anterior tarsal tunnel)** nerve injury",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660574613729,
    "question": "sural n. fibers originate from branches of the [...] and [...] nerves",
    "answer": "sural n. fibers originate from branches of the **tibial** and **common peroneal (fibular)** nerves",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660574731223,
    "question": "SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology:[...][...]trauma (e.g., laceration)",
    "answer": "SURAL NEUROPATHY, Etiology:**compression from tight socks****Baker’s/ganglion cyst**trauma (e.g., laceration)",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660574868491,
    "question": "sural neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...]EMG[...]",
    "answer": "sural neuropathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **Abnormal sural sensory**CMAP: **not applicable**EMG**Not applicable**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660584865380,
    "question": "superior gluteal n. course leaves the pelvis via the [...] [...] the piriformis muscle and divides into superior and inferior branchesinferior branch supplies [...]superior branch supplies the [...]",
    "answer": "superior gluteal n. course leaves the pelvis via the **greater sciatic foramen** **above** the piriformis muscle and divides into superior and inferior branchesinferior branch supplies **glute med, min, and TFL**superior branch supplies the **gluteus medius only** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660585022915,
    "question": "gluteal n. injury etiology [...][...][...]not hip dislocation / pelvic fracture",
    "answer": "gluteal n. injury etiology **hip joint replacement****improper IM injection****pelvic masses**not hip dislocation / pelvic fracture",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660585180134,
    "question": "gluteal n. injury clinical pressuperior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [...] and [...]. [...] will be seeninferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of [...].",
    "answer": "gluteal n. injury clinical pressuperior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of **hip abduction** and **internal/external rotation**. **Trendelenburg gait::phys-ex** will be seeninferior gluteal neuropathy: presents with weakness of **hip extension**.",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660586818671,
    "question": "Obturator n. course descends within the substance of the [...], emerging from its medial border at the pelvic brimdescends along the ala of the sacrum to reach the lateral pelvic wall on the [...] musclesweeps forward within the pelvis to reach and pass through the [...] to enter the thigh then it divides into anterior and posterior branches",
    "answer": "Obturator n. course descends within the substance of the **psoas major**, emerging from its medial border at the pelvic brimdescends along the ala of the sacrum to reach the lateral pelvic wall on the **obturator internus** musclesweeps forward within the pelvis to reach and pass through the **obturator foramen** to enter the thigh then it divides into anterior and posterior branches",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660587113470,
    "question": "Obturator Nerve Innervates...anterior branch[...][...][...][...]posterior branch [...][...]Sensory Branch[...] [...]",
    "answer": "Obturator Nerve Innervates...anterior branch**adductor longus****adductor brevis****gracilis****pectineus***posterior branch **obturator externus****adductor magnus^**Sensory Branch**articular knee joint** **medial aspect of the thigh** (Nerve roots per Preston & Shapiro)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660587473171,
    "question": "Obturator neuropathy, Etiology:[...][...][...]tumorgravid uterusgi surgery/positioning",
    "answer": "Obturator neuropathy, Etiology:**retroperitonneal hematoma****pelvic fracture****obturator hernia**tumorgravid uterusgi surgery/positioning",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660587596274,
    "question": "Obturator neuropathy, Clinical presentation:altered sensation in the [...] region (common)including pain, numbness, and/or paresthesiasweakness with hip [...] and [...]",
    "answer": "Obturator neuropathy, Clinical presentation:altered sensation in the **inguinal/medial thigh** region (common)including pain, numbness, and/or paresthesiasweakness with hip **ADduction** and **internal rotation**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660587685186,
    "question": "Obturator n. injury During ambulation, they present with a [...] and [...] gait",
    "answer": "Obturator n. injury During ambulation, they present with a **wide-based** and **circumducting** gait",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660587841056,
    "question": "Obturator neuroptathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: [...]CMAP: [...]EMGAbnormal activity: [...]",
    "answer": "Obturator neuroptathy, EDX findings:NCSSNAP: **None available**CMAP: **None available**EMGAbnormal activity: **in the obturator n. innervated m's (eg. adductor’s & gracillus)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660870959722,
    "question": "Peripheral Neuropathies categorized based on distribution effected they can be described as [...] or [...]",
    "answer": "Peripheral Neuropathies categorized based on distribution effected they can be described as **diffuse** or **multifocal**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660871625182,
    "question": "Inherited Peripheral Neuropathiestypically categorized as:[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Inherited Peripheral Neuropathiestypically categorized as:**Hereditary motor and sensory neuropathies (HMSN)****Hereditary sensory and autonomic neuropathies (HSAN)****Hereditary motor neuropathies (HMN)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660871742456,
    "question": "[...] aka [...] disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the [...] gene, located within the chromosome [...]",
    "answer": "**HMSN** aka **Charcot–Marie–Tooth** disease is the most commonly inherited peripheral polyneuropathy due to duplication mutation of the **PMP-22** gene, located within the chromosome **17p11. 2**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660871898661,
    "question": "Acquired Neuropathiesmost commonly related to:[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Acquired Neuropathiesmost commonly related to:**Diabetes mellitus (most common)****Acute inflammatory demyelinating polyradiculopathy (AIDP)****Medications**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660872097300,
    "question": "Acquired Peripheral Neuropathies[...] can manifest as a polyradiculopathy",
    "answer": "Acquired Peripheral Neuropathies**Demyelinating inflammatory neuropathies** can manifest as a polyradiculopathy",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660872292169,
    "question": "Clinical Presentation of Peripheral Polyneruopathies A classic triad has been described presenting in the lower limbs > upper limbs:[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Clinical Presentation of Peripheral Polyneruopathies A classic triad has been described presenting in the lower limbs > upper limbs:**Sensory changes in a stocking/glove distribution****Distal weakness****Diminished/absent Reflexes**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660872414800,
    "question": "Clinical Presentation of Poly Neuropathies acquired polyneuropathies:[...][...]inherited polyneuropathies:[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Clinical Presentation of Poly Neuropathies acquired polyneuropathies:**Burning / Pain::sx****Paresthesias::sx**inherited polyneuropathies:**Sensory loss::phys-ex/sx****Ataxia::phys-ex****muscle cramping::sx**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660872621828,
    "question": "EMG/NCSdiagnostic criteria for peripheral neuropathy consists of evaluating at least [...]",
    "answer": "EMG/NCSdiagnostic criteria for peripheral neuropathy consists of evaluating at least **three limbs**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660872880976,
    "question": "Peripheral NeuropathyEDX abnormalities can include:Prolonged latencies (o/l)Increased conduction velocities (CV)Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv)Decreased [...] (“missing” waveforms on [...] stimulations)Increased [...] (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on [...] stimulation \"duration\")",
    "answer": "Peripheral NeuropathyEDX abnormalities can include:Prolonged latencies (o/l)Increased conduction velocities (CV)Reduced or absent amplitudes (uv)Decreased **persistence** (“missing” waveforms on **repetitive::same** stimulations)Increased **chronodispersion** (large latency difference between the fastest and slowest waveform on **repetitive::same** stimulation \"duration\")",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660873371807,
    "question": "Ddx Foot Drop[...][...][...][...][...]",
    "answer": "Ddx Foot Drop**Central: Tumor, cerebrovascular accident (CVA), arteriovenous malformation (AVM), spinal cord injury (SCI)****Radiculopathy: L4–L5::2****Plexopathy****Mononeuropathy: peroneal (fibular) portion of the sciatic nerve, common peroneal (fibular), deep peroneal (fibular)::3****Diffuse polyneuropathy: Diabetes**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1660873646296,
    "question": "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth diseasethe PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with [...]. which presents with [...] and [...] episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",
    "answer": "In addition to Charcot–Marie–Tooth diseasethe PMP-22 gene is also implicated in hereditary neuropathy with **liability to pressure palsy (HNPP)**. which presents with **recurrent** and **short-term** episodes of motor and sensory mononeuropathies",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1661097058583,
    "question": "NCS in peripheral neruopathyConduction Block is more likely to be seen in [...] polyneuropathies",
    "answer": "NCS in peripheral neruopathyConduction Block is more likely to be seen in **acquired::inherited/acquired** polyneuropathies",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1661097187573,
    "question": "peripheral neuropathies classicaly present with stocking-glove patternThough less common, [...] may demonstrate abnormalities first",
    "answer": "peripheral neuropathies classicaly present with stocking-glove patternThough less common, **the upper limbs** may demonstrate abnormalities first",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1662309330327,
    "question": "ABductor HallucisInnervation is via the...[...] nerve[...] roots",
    "answer": "ABductor HallucisInnervation is via the...**medial plantar (tibial n, tibial division of the sciatic n, sacral plexus)** nerve**S1, S2** roots",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1662309866736,
    "question": "Extensor Digitorum Brevis Innervation is via the... [...] nerve[...] roots",
    "answer": "Extensor Digitorum Brevis Innervation is via the... **deep peroneal** nerve**L5, S1** roots",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1673315693225,
    "question": "[...] needle electrode",
    "answer": "**Single-fiber** needle electrode",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698072349804,
    "question": "EMG Special StudiesSmall nerve fiber abnormalities and associated [...] dysfunctionmay not be seen with conventional NCS and can require additional tests",
    "answer": "EMG Special StudiesSmall nerve fiber abnormalities and associated **autonomic** dysfunctionmay not be seen with conventional NCS and can require additional tests",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698072428074,
    "question": "EMG Special StudiesFurthermore, small fiber neuropathies manifest as [...] in the extremities with abnormal pinprick sensation but demonstrate [...] standard NCS",
    "answer": "EMG Special StudiesFurthermore, small fiber neuropathies manifest as **burning pain::sx** in the extremities with abnormal pinprick sensation but demonstrate **normal** standard NCS",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698073028485,
    "question": "[...] Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories)[...][...] [...] [...] [...]",
    "answer": "**Axonal** Peripheral Neuropathy ddx (broad categories)**HMSN-II::inherited disorder****Heavy metals: Lead, Gold, Mercury** **Cancer drugs: Vincristine, Cis-platinum** **Metabolic derangements: alcohol, B12 deficiency, folate deficiency** **Auto-immune: paraneoplastic syndrome, Sjogren's, Crohn's, Sarcoidosis**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698073351226,
    "question": "HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: AbnormalCMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by [...]%No [...]No [...]No [...] EMG[...]",
    "answer": "HMSN I: CHARCOT-MARIE-TOOTH Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: AbnormalCMAP: Abnormal, CV decreased by **70**%No **temporal dispersion**No **conduction block**No **focal slowing (diffuse slowing** EMG**Normal**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698073731663,
    "question": "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsNCSSNAP: [...]CMAP:[...] CV / o/p latecny[...]: amplitudeNCS CMAP will be positive for [...][...][...] [...]: [...] EMG [...]",
    "answer": "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsNCSSNAP: **Abnormal**CMAP:**Abnormal** CV / o/p latecny**normal (unless poor prognosis)**: amplitudeNCS CMAP will be positive for **temporal dispersion****conduction block****focal slowing** **F-wave**: **Abnormal—first EDX sign** EMG **typically Normal (unless axonal variant)**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698073824473,
    "question": "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsPoorer prognosis if:CMAP: Amplitude <[...]% of normal NCV <[...]% of normal[...]EMG: [...]",
    "answer": "AIDP (GBS) and CIDP Edx findingsPoorer prognosis if:CMAP: Amplitude <**20**% of normal NCV <**40**% of normal**F-wave: Absent**EMG: **Abnormal activity (axonal involvement)**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698074457938,
    "question": "HIV-Related Neuropathies[...]: most common type of neuropathyprimarily affects [...] and [...] fibersparesthesias begin in the [...] followed by the [...]",
    "answer": "HIV-Related Neuropathies**Distal Symmetric Poly-neuropathy**: most common type of neuropathyprimarily affects **sensory** and **autonomic** fibersparesthesias begin in the **toes** followed by the **fingers**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698586431927,
    "question": "NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low [...] causes the amplitude of the [...] to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber APThis occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content",
    "answer": "NMJ disorders hinder the production, release, or uptake of ACh a low **safety factor** causes the amplitude of the **endplate potentials** to fall below the threshold needed to generate a muscle fiber APThis occurs due to an alteration of quantal response or content",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698586614202,
    "question": "Myasthenia gravis (MG): disorder resulting in a decreased quantal response due to an autoimmune response against postsynaptic ACh receptorsleads to [...] [...] amplitudes, and [...] frequency (quantal content is normal)",
    "answer": "Myasthenia gravis (MG): disorder resulting in a decreased quantal response due to an autoimmune response against postsynaptic ACh receptorsleads to **reduced** **miniature endplate potential (MEPP)** amplitudes, and **normal** frequency (quantal content is normal)",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698586679571,
    "question": "Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS, myasthenic syndrome): disorder resulting in decreased quantal content leaving the presynaptic cleft, resulting in [...] MEPP amplitudes with [...] frequency (quantal response is normal)",
    "answer": "Lambert–Eaton myasthenic syndrome (LEMS, myasthenic syndrome): disorder resulting in decreased quantal content leaving the presynaptic cleft, resulting in **normal** MEPP amplitudes with **decreased** frequency (quantal response is normal)",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698587203068,
    "question": "MG pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response in which polyclonal antibodies are directed against the Muscle Specific Tyrosine Kinase (MuSK) of the [...]",
    "answer": "MG pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response in which polyclonal antibodies are directed against the Muscle Specific Tyrosine Kinase (MuSK) of the **postsynaptic membrane**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698587321136,
    "question": "LEMS pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response against the voltage gated [...] channels on the [...] membrane",
    "answer": "LEMS pathophysdisorder of neuromuscular transmission due to an autoimmune response against the voltage gated **P/Q Ca2+** channels on the **presynaptic** membrane",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698613895401,
    "question": "In MG MSR are [...]In LEMS MSR are [...]",
    "answer": "In MG MSR are **normal**In LEMS MSR are **abnormal**",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698613966047,
    "question": "Myesthenia Gravis DxLabs[...][...]",
    "answer": "Myesthenia Gravis DxLabs**Anti-Ach receptor antibodies****Anti-MuSK antibodies**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698613999568,
    "question": "Lambert Eaton DxLabsAntibodies against [...]",
    "answer": "Lambert Eaton DxLabsAntibodies against **voltage-gated Ca+ channels**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614182352,
    "question": "NMJ disorders muscle biopsy MG[...] of the postjunctional membrane with loss of junctional folds and receptorsLEMS[...] of neuromuscular junction with decreased active zones",
    "answer": "NMJ disorders muscle biopsy MG**Simplification** of the postjunctional membrane with loss of junctional folds and receptorsLEMS**Overdevelopment** of neuromuscular junction with decreased active zones",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614339816,
    "question": "Evaluation of NMJ d/o involves typical NCS with EMG, as well as the addition of [...] and [...]",
    "answer": "Evaluation of NMJ d/o involves typical NCS with EMG, as well as the addition of **repetitive nerve stimulations (RNSs)** and **single-fiber EMG (SFEMG)**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614538656,
    "question": "NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS:SNAP: [...]^CMAP: [...]& o/p latency and conduction velocity [...]* amplitude except in [...]",
    "answer": "NMJ disorders EDx findings NCS:SNAP: **normal**^CMAP: **normal**& o/p latency and conduction velocity **variable (MG: normal)*** amplitude except in **LEMS**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614653830,
    "question": "NMJ d/o EdxIf low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a [...] [...], followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >[...]% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",
    "answer": "NMJ d/o EdxIf low CMAP amplitude, should be followed by a **10 second::time** **maximum voluntary contraction**, followed by a single stimulation. Increased amplitudes >**100**% compared with premaximum contraction are seen in LEMS",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614743939,
    "question": "NMJ d/o EdxCMAP amplitude will show >[...]% [...] on low rate rep. stim",
    "answer": "NMJ d/o EdxCMAP amplitude will show >**10**% **decrement** on low rate rep. stim",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698614911244,
    "question": "NMJ disorder Edx findingsEMG: Can be normal or abnormalIn severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen[...], [...] MUAPs with [...] recruitment are associated with [...]MUAPs become [...]",
    "answer": "NMJ disorder Edx findingsEMG: Can be normal or abnormalIn severe cases, abnormal spontaneous activity can be seen**Short-duration**, **low-amplitude** MUAPs with **early** recruitment are associated with **blocking::SFEMG parameter**MUAPs become **unstable**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698615055320,
    "question": "Myesthenia Gravis Treatment [...][...]CorticosteroidsImmunosuppressive agentsPlasmapheresisIV Immunoglobulin",
    "answer": "Myesthenia Gravis Treatment **Thymectomy****Anticholinesterase drugs: Pyridostigmine**CorticosteroidsImmunosuppressive agentsPlasmapheresisIV Immunoglobulin",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698615157413,
    "question": "Lambert Eaton SnydrometreatmentTreat [...][...][...]: Increases ACh quanta3,4-diaminopyridine",
    "answer": "Lambert Eaton SnydrometreatmentTreat **malignancy****Immunosuppressives: Corticosteroids, steroid-sparing agents, PLEX, IVIG::category****Guanidine**: Increases ACh quanta3,4-diaminopyridine",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1698615238655,
    "question": "Botulismtreatment [...] in first [...] hoursSupportive with intubation for respiratory failureRecovery occurs from collateral sprouting",
    "answer": "Botulismtreatment **trivalent ABE antitoxin** in first **24** hoursSupportive with intubation for respiratory failureRecovery occurs from collateral sprouting",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705599486655,
    "question": "[...]: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to [...]",
    "answer": "**Arthrogryposis**: a fixed deformity of the extremities due to **intrauterine hypomobility**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705599990528,
    "question": "Myopathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: [...]^^CMAP: [...] amplitude**[...] latencies and conduction velocities&&EMGClassic findings: are [...], [...], [...] MUAP's with [...] recruitment Resting activity: [...], [...], [...]",
    "answer": "Myopathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: **Normal**^^CMAP: **typically normal, (Decreased in significant atrophy/preferential distal m.'s)** amplitude****Normal** latencies and conduction velocities&&EMGClassic findings: are **low amplitude**, **short duration**, **polyphasic** MUAP's with **early** recruitment Resting activity: **fibs/sharps**, **myotonic discharges**, **CRD's (depends on the type of disorder)**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705600055647,
    "question": "Quantitative EMGprovides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform [...], which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing [...]. The mean [...] is calculated using [...] MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line.",
    "answer": "Quantitative EMGprovides a more detailed measurement of the MUAPs. It is a better indication of waveform **duration::same**, which is a sensitive parameter for diagnosing **myopathies**. The mean **duration::same** is calculated using **20::#** MUAPs and on a screen set with a trigger and delay line.",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705600246289,
    "question": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationshort-duration, small amplitudepossible causedue to [...]",
    "answer": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationshort-duration, small amplitudepossible causedue to **loss of muscle fibers**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705600318139,
    "question": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationlong-duration, large amplitudepossible causethese polyphasic potentials are due to [...]",
    "answer": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentationlong-duration, large amplitudepossible causethese polyphasic potentials are due to **collateral sprouting**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705600493013,
    "question": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentation[...]possible causevariable amplitude potentials are due to [...] of [...], formed at the beginning of [...]",
    "answer": "Recruitment: Early Onset With Minimal Effort (myopathies)MUAP presentation**Unstable**possible causevariable amplitude potentials are due to **blocking** of **immature NMJs**, formed at the beginning of **collateral sprouting**",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705601463152,
    "question": "MyopathiesRepetitive Nerve StimulationA normal or a decremental response can occurThis is due to the [...] found in regenerating immature NMJs that form during recovery or reinnervation",
    "answer": "MyopathiesRepetitive Nerve StimulationA normal or a decremental response can occurThis is due to the **reduced safety factor** found in regenerating immature NMJs that form during recovery or reinnervation",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705601700676,
    "question": "MyopathiesSingle-Fiber EMG (may demonstrate):[...][...][...]",
    "answer": "MyopathiesSingle-Fiber EMG (may demonstrate):**increased jitter****increased fiber density (FD)****increased blocking**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705601821176,
    "question": "TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY[...] [...]Fiber type disproportion",
    "answer": "TYPE I FIBER ATROPHY**Myotonic Dystrophy** **Nemaline rod myopathy**Fiber type disproportion",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705601871067,
    "question": "TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY[...][...]Deconditioning",
    "answer": "TYPE II FIBER ATROPHY**Steroid myopathy****Myasthenia gravis**Deconditioning",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705602018547,
    "question": "FSH, facioscapulohumeralinheritance: [...]",
    "answer": "FSH, facioscapulohumeralinheritance: **autosomal dominant**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705602109923,
    "question": "Central Core disease is associated with [...]",
    "answer": "Central Core disease is associated with **malignant hyperthermia**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705602339071,
    "question": "Inclusion Body Myositisetiology: unkownpresentation: [...], painless weakness in proximal and distal muscles onset: affects [...]Edx findings: unique to myopathy [...]treatment: no treatment",
    "answer": "Inclusion Body Myositisetiology: unkownpresentation: **assymetric**, painless weakness in proximal and distal muscles onset: affects **adults age 45-55 (peaks at 70)::epidimiology**Edx findings: unique to myopathy **abnormal NCS (assoc w/ polyneuropathy)**treatment: no treatment",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705603400131,
    "question": "SMA, spinal muscle atrophyportion of motor neuron affected[...]",
    "answer": "SMA, spinal muscle atrophyportion of motor neuron affected**lower motor neuron**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705603481394,
    "question": "motor neuron disease [...][...]portion of motor neuron affectedupper motor neuron",
    "answer": "motor neuron disease **PLS, primary lateral sclerosis****Hereditary spastic paraplegia**portion of motor neuron affectedupper motor neuron",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705603542062,
    "question": "Motor Neuron DiseaseIt is important to rule out treatable neuropathies that mimic motor neuron disease (MND). An example of this is [...], which includes conduction block and temporal dispersion, not seen in MND.",
    "answer": "Motor Neuron DiseaseIt is important to rule out treatable neuropathies that mimic motor neuron disease (MND). An example of this is **multifocal motor neuropathy**, which includes conduction block and temporal dispersion, not seen in MND.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705603808912,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsNCSSNAP: [...]** CMAP:[...]: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies^^ [...]: amplitude&&F-wave: [...], [...] with [...]",
    "answer": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsNCSSNAP: **normal**** CMAP:**typicaly normal**: conduction velocities and onselt/distal latencies^^ **reduced**: amplitude&&F-wave: **Abnormal latency**, **persistence** with **chronodispersion**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604036733,
    "question": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsEMGStudy at least [...] limbsClassic Needle Finding: [...] and [...]must be found in [...] of [...] body segmentsAt least [...] muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "answer": "Motor Neuron Disease Edx findingsEMGStudy at least **3** limbsClassic Needle Finding: **Active denervation with reinnervation::in general** and **fasciculations::MUAP morphology**must be found in **3** of **4 (craniobulbar, cervical, thoracic, and lumbosacral)** body segmentsAt least **2** muscles with different innervations should be abnormal",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604444081,
    "question": "[...]:degradation of neural tissue due to multiple medical complications causing a primarily axonal as well as demyelinating motor and sensory peripheral polyneuropathy",
    "answer": "**critical illness polyneuropathy (CIP)**:degradation of neural tissue due to multiple medical complications causing a primarily axonal as well as demyelinating motor and sensory peripheral polyneuropathy",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604514949,
    "question": "[...]:an acute, generally inflammatory myopathy due to multiple medical complications causing muscle membrane instability and muscle cell breakdown",
    "answer": "**critical illness myopathy (CIM)**:an acute, generally inflammatory myopathy due to multiple medical complications causing muscle membrane instability and muscle cell breakdown",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604754425,
    "question": "CNS disorders Edx FindingsIn CNS disorders, sensory and motor NCSs are normal.On needle EMG, there is no denervation or reinnervation on the weak limb(s); it reveals normal spontaneous activity and normal MUAP morphology. On voluntary contraction, recruitment is [...]",
    "answer": "CNS disorders Edx FindingsIn CNS disorders, sensory and motor NCSs are normal.On needle EMG, there is no denervation or reinnervation on the weak limb(s); it reveals normal spontaneous activity and normal MUAP morphology. On voluntary contraction, recruitment is **normal**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604833796,
    "question": "SCI edx findings will EMG be abdnormal: [...]",
    "answer": "SCI edx findings will EMG be abdnormal: **yes (at the level of the lesion)**",
    "category": "Study Notes",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705604994520,
    "question": "paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS)related cancerssmall cell lung cancer [...][...]",
    "answer": "paraneoplastic neurologic syndromes (PNS)related cancerssmall cell lung cancer **lymphoma****myeloma**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705605192334,
    "question": "Paraneoplastic Syndrome can affect the CNS e.g.[...] and paraneoplastic [...]",
    "answer": "Paraneoplastic Syndrome can affect the CNS e.g.**limbic encephalitis (hippocampus and amygdala)** and paraneoplastic **cerebellar degeneration**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705605280038,
    "question": "In ALS [...], [...], and [...] are spared",
    "answer": "In ALS **bowel**, **bladder**, and **sensation** are spared",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705605630890,
    "question": "Repetitive nerve stimulation:These are studies in which a [...] [...] stimulation of a motor nerve is performed.A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic [...].",
    "answer": "Repetitive nerve stimulation:These are studies in which a **repeated** **supramaximal** stimulation of a motor nerve is performed.A series of CMAPs are recorded and evaluated for pathologic **amplitude changes**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705605825351,
    "question": "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation (RNS) SETUP[...] the electrode[...] the limbStimulate at a supramaximal levelOptimize limb temperature (approximately [...])Minimize [...]Stop [...]Muscles should be evaluated in a [...] progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated)",
    "answer": "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation (RNS) SETUP**Immobilize** the electrode**Immobilize** the limbStimulate at a supramaximal levelOptimize limb temperature (approximately **30°C**)Minimize **electrode gel**Stop **anticholinesterase inhibitors**Muscles should be evaluated in a **distal to proximal** progression (if an abnormality is suspected but not demonstrated)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705605875689,
    "question": "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ABNORMALITYA >[...]% decrease in amplitude from the [...] to [...] waveform is significant for pathology",
    "answer": "Repetitive Nerve Stimulation ABNORMALITYA >**10**% decrease in amplitude from the **1st** to **5th** waveform is significant for pathology",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606092506,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [...] to [...] HzEach stimulus causes the [...] amplitude to drop. If the [...] is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the [...] amplitude",
    "answer": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:This repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of **2** to **3** HzEach stimulus causes the **EPP** amplitude to drop. If the **safety factor** is decreased, the potential will fall below the threshold necessary for activation. This results in a decrease of the **MUAP** amplitude",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606211188,
    "question": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >[...]% amplitude reduction between the [...] and [...] waveformsAn increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of [...]A typical [...] decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "answer": "Low-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:An abnormality is considered when a CMAP demonstrates >**10**% amplitude reduction between the **1st** and **4th** waveformsAn increase in waveform can be seen if more stimulations are provided due to mobilization of **secondary ACh stores**A typical **U-shaped** decrement can be seen in myasthenia gravis",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606483378,
    "question": "[...]:After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second [...] or [...] stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",
    "answer": "**Postactivation Facilitation (PAF)**:After a decrement is noted with LRRS, a 30-60 second **isometric contraction** or **tetany-producing** stimulation (50 Hz) should be performed. demonstrates a repair in the CMAP amplitude with an immediate follow up LRRS because of an improvement in neuromuscular transmission.",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606612331,
    "question": "[...]:This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a [...] performed every [...] for [...] after an initial 30-60-second isometric contractionThis test should be used if a [...] is not seen with the initial [...], but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",
    "answer": "**Postactivation Exhaustion (PAE)**:This response is seen as a CMAP amplitude decreases. It occurs with a **LRRS::same** performed every **minute** for **5 minutes** after an initial 30-60-second isometric contractionThis test should be used if a **decrement** is not seen with the initial **LRRS::same**, but a diagnosis of a NMJ disorder is suspected",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606836309,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of [...] to [...] Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists [...] and repairs the waveformstypically performed if a patient is unable to perform a [...] [...]",
    "answer": "High-Rate Repetitive Stimulation:repetitive stimulation test is performed at a rate of **10** to **50** Hz. It causes an accumulation of calcium in the cell, which assists **ACh release** and repairs the waveformstypically performed if a patient is unable to perform a **30- to 60-second::time** ** maximal isometric contraction**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705606938148,
    "question": "High-Rate Repetitive StimulationNMJ disease and Amplitude Changes[...] = 200%–300% increment[...] = Decrement demonstrated and partially repaired",
    "answer": "High-Rate Repetitive StimulationNMJ disease and Amplitude Changes**LEMS** = 200%–300% increment**MG** = Decrement demonstrated and partially repaired",
    "category": "Nerve Conduction",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705608346612,
    "question": "Pseudofacilitation a normal reaction and demonstrates a progressive increase in [...] with HRRS or voluntary muscle contraction",
    "answer": "Pseudofacilitation a normal reaction and demonstrates a progressive increase in **CMAP amplitude** with HRRS or voluntary muscle contraction",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705608406408,
    "question": "PseudofacilitationIt represents a decrease in [...] due to increased [...] of muscle fiber contraction",
    "answer": "PseudofacilitationIt represents a decrease in **temporal dispersion** due to increased **synchronicity** of muscle fiber contraction",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705608757494,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMGThis is a study that monitors the parameters of single muscle fiber APs. It is useful if [...] is normal (and an abnormal diagnosis is still suspected)",
    "answer": "Single Fiber EMGThis is a study that monitors the parameters of single muscle fiber APs. It is useful if **repetitive stimulation** is normal (and an abnormal diagnosis is still suspected)",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705608811032,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMGSFEMG is the most sensitive test for [...] but has low specificityAbnormalities can also be associated with [...], and [...]",
    "answer": "Single Fiber EMGSFEMG is the most sensitive test for **NMJ disorders** but has low specificityAbnormalities can also be associated with **motor neuron disorders**, and **peripheral neuropathies**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705609068483,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG ParamtersFiber densityrepresents the number of [...] belonging to the same [...] within the recording radius of the electrodeA FD of [...] is normal. Higher than this represents a [...] process",
    "answer": "Single Fiber EMG ParamtersFiber densityrepresents the number of **single muscle fibers** belonging to the same **motor unit** within the recording radius of the electrodeA FD of **1.5::decimal** is normal. Higher than this represents a **denervation and reinnervation** process",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705609548120,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters[...]:caused by a increased delay in the [...] [...] of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve injury results in poor activation of the immature NMJs",
    "answer": "Single Fiber EMG Paramters**Jitter**:caused by a increased delay in the **inter-potential** **discharges** of two muscle fibers belonging to the same motor unit (normally 10 to 60 μsec) Disorders of neuromuscular transmission affect the safety factor and cause a delay in the time for an EPP to reach threshold for a muscle fiber AP, Reinnervation through collateral sprouting after a nerve injury results in poor activation of the immature NMJs",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705609677196,
    "question": "Single Fiber EMG parameters[...]:This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP [...]It occurs if the jitter becomes >[...] μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",
    "answer": "Single Fiber EMG parameters**Blocking**:This is an abnormality that occurs when a single muscle fiber AP **fails to appear**It occurs if the jitter becomes >**100** μsec. It typically resolves in approximately 1 to 3 months, after reinnervation is completed. However, the increased jitter may take approximately 6 months to resolve",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705676555483,
    "question": "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: [...]: amplitude[...]: CV o/p latencyCMAP: [...]: amplitude[...]: CV o/p latencyEMG[...] seen in [...] musclesrecruitment patter: [...]",
    "answer": "Critical Illness Neuropathy Edx FindingsNCSSNAP: **low/unobtainable**: amplitude**mild slowing**: CV o/p latencyCMAP: **low/unobtainable**: amplitude**mild slowing (primarily axonal)**: CV o/p latencyEMG**Fibs/sharps** seen in **distal** musclesrecruitment patter: **neuropathic (decreased with high frequency)**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705676719708,
    "question": "Critical Illness Myopathy Edx Findingsin general will present exactly the same as [...]",
    "answer": "Critical Illness Myopathy Edx Findingsin general will present exactly the same as **myopathies**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705678128655,
    "question": "[...]:a means of evaluating the unmyelinated, [...] nerve fibers of the PNS",
    "answer": "**Sympathetic skin response**:a means of evaluating the unmyelinated, **sympathetic::same** nerve fibers of the PNS",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705678658015,
    "question": "Sinus arrhythmia study: aka [...] study dependent on the normal [...] that occur with [...] via parasympathetic activitytest consists of measuring the [...] with an [...] machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",
    "answer": "Sinus arrhythmia study: aka **cardio-vagal innervation** study dependent on the normal **heart rate variations** that occur with **respiration** via parasympathetic activitytest consists of measuring the **R-R ratio** with an **EKG** machine attached to the amplifier of the EMG.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705678741145,
    "question": "[...] study:heart rate varies in response to changes in blood pressure and intrathoracic pressure via sympathetic and parasympathetic activity. Four phases are measured using a standard EMG machine. The findings measured in Phase 2 and Phase 4 are used for monitoring. Phase 2 should demonstrate a heart rate increase, while Phase 4 should demonstrate a decrease in the normal population.",
    "answer": "**Valsalva ratio** study:heart rate varies in response to changes in blood pressure and intrathoracic pressure via sympathetic and parasympathetic activity. Four phases are measured using a standard EMG machine. The findings measured in Phase 2 and Phase 4 are used for monitoring. Phase 2 should demonstrate a heart rate increase, while Phase 4 should demonstrate a decrease in the normal population.",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705678820786,
    "question": "Anal sphincter activity:EMG recording of the external anal sphincter has [...] activity at rest.",
    "answer": "Anal sphincter activity:EMG recording of the external anal sphincter has **continuous** activity at rest.",
    "category": "Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705678973246,
    "question": "Autonomic Nerve Studies[...]Sympathetic Skin ResponseSinus ArryhthmiaValsalva RatioAnal Sphincter Activity",
    "answer": "Autonomic Nerve Studies**Norepinephrine synthesis and release**Sympathetic Skin ResponseSinus ArryhthmiaValsalva RatioAnal Sphincter Activity",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705684472999,
    "question": "AIDP clinical presentationsx's worst at [...] after onset [...] ascending paralysis[...][...] and [...] muscle may be affected [...]",
    "answer": "AIDP clinical presentationsx's worst at **4 weeks::time** after onset **symmetric::symmetric/asymmetric** ascending paralysis**absent reflexes****bulbar (bell's plasy)** and **respiratory** muscle may be affected **autonomic dysfunction**",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705685690177,
    "question": "CIDP can present identical to AIDPCIDP should be considered:If the disease progresses for more than [...] or if [...]",
    "answer": "CIDP can present identical to AIDPCIDP should be considered:If the disease progresses for more than **8 weeks** or if **the patient relapses**",
    "category": "Clinical Conditions",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705687535103,
    "question": "[...]: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an [...] [...] disorder",
    "answer": "**Multifocal Motor Neuropathy**: a chronic inflammatory neuropathy that presents as an **assymetric::symetric/assymetric** **pure motor::sensory/motor/mixed** disorder",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705847730502,
    "question": "Firing Rate:This is the number of times a [...]. It is expressed in [...] and is calculated by dividing [...] by the [...]. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using [...]",
    "answer": "Firing Rate:This is the number of times a ** MUAP fires per second**. It is expressed in **Hz** and is calculated by dividing **1,000::#** by the **interspike interval (II)**. take care to look at the units and make sure you are using **msec**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705849033291,
    "question": "[...]:this is defined as the [...] of the [...] when [...]Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a [...] process",
    "answer": "**Recruitment frequency (RF)**:this is defined as the **Firing Rate** of the **1st MUAP** when **a 2nd MUAP begins to fire**Values above normal (20 Hz or below) correlate with a **neuropathic** process",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705849404362,
    "question": "[...]:This is the [...] between two discharges of the [...] when [...]. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately [...] msec",
    "answer": "**Recruitment interval (RI)**:This is the **interspike interval (in milliseconds)** between two discharges of the **(same) 1st MUAP** when **a second MUAP begins to fire**. It is initiated by an increase in the force of a contraction. Normal is considered approximately **100** msec",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705849527474,
    "question": "Decreased RI (Increased RF):would be consistent with a [...]",
    "answer": "Decreased RI (Increased RF):would be consistent with a **neuropathic process**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705849585386,
    "question": "Increased RI (Decreased RF):is consistent with a [...]",
    "answer": "Increased RI (Decreased RF):is consistent with a **myopathic process**",
    "category": "General Knowledge",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705849960072,
    "question": "[...]:This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the [...] of the [...] by the [...]. The normal RR is considered <[...]",
    "answer": "**Recruitment ratio (RR)**:This has been used to represent recruitment capabilities, especially when a patient demonstrates difficulty in controlling a contractile force. It is calculated by dividing the **Firing Rate** of the **first MUAP** by the **number of different MUAPs on the screen**. The normal RR is considered <**10**",
    "category": "EMG Findings",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 1705850435876,
    "question": "[...] PatternsThis is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs.It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during [...]. It is composed of [...] plus [...].It can be decreased in [...] and [...].",
    "answer": "**Interference** PatternsThis is a qualitative or quantitative description of the sequential appearance of MUAPs.It is the electrical activity recorded from a muscle during **a maximum voluntary contraction**. It is composed of **recruitment** plus **activation**.It can be decreased in **CNS diseases** and **poor patient cooperation (pain, hysteria)**.",
    "category": "Muscle Anatomy",
    "type": "cloze_deletion"
  }
]